what you're listening to right now is
just an intro with me if you would like
to skip that intro feel free man value
your time go ahead and look down in the
description there should be a time that
the actual conversation with Megan
starts hello everybody Welcome to the
junkyard love podcast it's me your host
Mojo Jojo from The Powerpuff Girls
that's right it's the monkey with the
hat I'm coming to you live right now
from the back of an asteroid from a
comet from uh from a giant space Rock
orbiting planet Earth I just so happen
to have you know enough podcast
reception to record this intro for you I
would sit down a little sit down a
little base layer a little Foundation of
what we're about to explore on this
episode with Megan Hawkins from better
you psychedelic therapy better you is
the company that I went through to do at
home ketamine therapy you essentially
have a consultation a conversation with
somebody video chat
um get your stuff all figured out out
ask them whatever questions that you
have you go through questionnaires
whatever whatever and then they send the
kit to your house I think it goes
through a pharmacy if I either way you
have to you have to sign for it when it
gets to your house but uh inside the kit
there's a blindfold there's a blood
pressure cuff there is a journal there
is the ketamine it's in a trophy troche
t-r-o-c-h-e I feel like it's pronounced
different every everybody that I talked
to I never know which way to say but
this thing that dissolves on the inside
of your lip or under your tongue and
um that is the that is the medicine
itself but anyway you are also
um accompanied with it is a portal that
you have uh online you basically have a
profile
um I'm not sure if they have an app
maybe it's an app now as well but um it
walks you through everything you know
there's there's chapters there's
different sessions so if you're doing
your first one you click on that it
gives you Journal prompts to write it
gives you all the reminders like this
whole thing you're set up for Success
from the beginning you know
um to do your at-home ketamine session
they give you all the 4-1-1 of of what
to do how to set up your day itself how
to treat the days in between
how often to do it usually it's two two
trips a week and I say trips it's a
psychedelic trip but technically Academy
is not a psychedelic actually there's a
lot of interesting articles on that that
I've been reading it's um uh it's a
little bit brainier than I can fully
wrap my head around but uh some of the
examples are nice but you do have what I
would say a psychedelic trip I I had
read that it wasn't a psychedelic and it
was a disassociative and
um I mean to be honest I found it to be
much more like I've done mushrooms magic
mushrooms psilocybin in the in the past
and I really found it to be quite
similar to magic mushrooms
um I had a friend use the term
Cosmic when it came to ketamine and so
there's something right about that
ketamine does seem to be a bit more
Cosmic than the uh the trip on
psilocybin magic mushrooms but
nonetheless you are set up through this
company they give you everything that
you need they give you the support along
the way they give you the process you
know what to do the day of you know what
to do during you know what to do after
um it's it's great stuff I mean some
some of the journal prompts are just
fantastic I found myself writing a ton
for all these
um
and there's just a lot to be said about
this stuff there's a lot to be said
about the changes in personality
identity mood self
um the holding on that that we all have
with with our various you know ailments
and and
there's I don't know there's a I want to
allow Megan the space to explain these
things so much more elegantly and
um um you know eloquently even than I
possibly can
um which she does in this episode but I
um I think as as a base layer
it's certainly very interesting this is
there's something about this there's
something very good about this there's
even you know this has only been a
couple months for me since I've done it
and there's still things I feel like
unfolding you know
um there is as Megan says psychedelics
will will often give you what you need
not exactly what you want and there is
some sort of Truth to that there's like
some
um acceptance of things in life that
seems to come afterwards but uh
regardless I would suggest I I had kind
of gotten a little sloppy admittedly on
my last three trips I was doing a lot of
traveling for work and I had a lot of
eagerness about
um about doing these do doing this whole
process so
um I kind of like split up my last half
of the sessions in a way that probably
wasn't as good I should have like I just
I waited too far in between and I was
traveling so I would like skip a week in
between or whatever I think there's some
powerful
um attributes to be said towards the the
eight consecutive sessions if you have
that availability it's two sessions a
week
um
yeah man if you guys want I they
actually sent me
um I'm so happy they said this is the
cool thing about having a podcast they
sent me some Swag like so I got some uh
some better you shirts and and hat and
tote and just super cool uh so sweet of
them and they also sent me um some 100
off gift cards so if you
um I don't know if you're a fan of the
podcast hit me up email me
um message me text me if you have my
phone number and uh if you're planning
on doing this might as well get 100
bucks off I did want to also mention the
word disassociative that's a huge word
that you hear in the world of ketamine
that was a that was a mad turn off for
me I actually really was kind of about
that word
um if you've dealt with any sort of
you know any variation of these things
that you're coming here with depression
anxiety PTSD whatever you've probably
actually experienced the scarier crappy
version of disassociation
depersonalization derealization dpdr is
also known on some subreddits
um I used to have a I used to have some
issues with this and um
I I would say that I I really don't find
that to be a great word to use
interchange and changeably for uh this
this ketamine trip this ketamine
experience that you have I I just maybe
it's similar but I if I had it my way I
would use entirely different words
um it just seems like the experience
that I had under the under the ketamine
is quite different than than that I
would consider to be disassociation
um that I've dealt with in the past so I
just want to throw that out there just
because that was something I totally
forgot to ask Megan about but uh it was
something that was really kind of like
loud to me
um at the beginning that would have
actually kind of been helpful if
somebody said like ah maybe it's not
exactly what you what you think it is um
perhaps I'm going to be wrong and maybe
everybody's definition of disassociation
is going to be vastly different it's
such a strange experience anyway but um
uh if there's things that we didn't
cover in this podcast if there's things
that I didn't cover in the in the intro
um if there's if you have questions man
just reach out as I say that in the
podcast but just reach out to better you
if you're interested in this I feel like
they're more than willing to explain and
get you along for the ride or you know
make you feel better about uh anything
you know that you're nervous or confused
about I will leave you with this one
thing I just want to say follow follow
all of their prompts follow their portal
do what they say to do
um uh go go through the process the way
that they lay it out and and do all of
it and like just be serious about
getting this stuff on your calendar
setting the time aside like don't be
lackluster
um and then so and once once you do all
that then just stinking out loud like
once you have that blindfold on once
that music thing is is going once you're
in the world of that playlist for the
next you know 90 minutes to two hours
just do whatever is just allow whatever
is happening I mean I would do some
strange things that like were really
healing and Powerful to me I was like
drumming on my chest and you know kind
of like writhing comfortably and gently
you know in my bed I'm singing and
humming kind of you know it's there was
a bunch of like strange vocal tonality
frequency sort of things that seem to be
happening that just felt really good to
allow them to happen you know I think if
there was somebody sitting next to me if
I was nervous about like who could hear
me or or if someone's seeing me I might
be less prone to do those things um and
I'm just I'm just really aware of that
like we have this self-conscious nature
of of can I allow this thing that feels
so natural to to work through me without
my constricting hands and I think just
for this I would like to say allow it
allow it do whatever weird stuff maybe
you don't move your body at all and
that's your experience that's super cool
maybe you don't sing or hum or nothing
at all that's super cool too but if you
do have the inclination to do those
sorts of things you know keep it safe
listen to the instructions you know
you're on something that is
um lessening in many ways your motor
functions so so you know be smart but I
don't know just allow yourself to
experience this thing and and really uh
be willing to to kind of accept what's
on the other side I think it has
potential to be a beautiful experience
anyway this uh please read the
description below any info you need to
know you should be able to go down below
and click on links hit me up for the
hundred dollars off
um you know and then as usual please if
wherever you're at leave a review like
subscribe comment if any of that share
with anybody who needs it and feel free
to ask me
um anything that you need to know that I
can help with and I leave you in the
very capable hands of Megan Hawkins you
guys are going to love this episode
you're gonna love the way that she lays
everything out analogies metaphors
personal experiences um some stuff that
she's learned from from working with
patients she shares a lot of her her
personal background too after we get
into it for a while she actually kind of
tells the story of uh how she landed
where she is today it's this like an
unbelievable story too so
um yeah stick around for that I know
it's a long one but you know if there's
a lot of important stuff from the
beginning and to the middle end to end
honestly so maybe this is one that you
don't sit down and listen to for the
entirety of it but you just listen to it
in 20 to 30 minute chunks throughout the
next couple days regardless get it in
there there's lots of good stuff there's
a lot of people who could benefit from
this information you're going to love
Megan here we go guys thanks for
listening to the junkyard love podcast
we'll catch you next time
at what age should we learn to have
better conversations with ourselves
[Music]
knowledge is power
reality is
we'll assume going into the podcast that
I've basically given you like like a
partial introduction but I think I'll
probably spend you know 5-10 minutes as
my little intro basically saying hey I
did ketamine therapy here's what it was
here's the company I got this person on
from this I kind of give them a little
bit of a basis because I I definitely
want to bring in complete newcomers like
people who don't know anything about
psychedelics people don't know anything
about ketamine any of that as much as I
like definitely want to go into the
weeds if that's where we go I just want
to give people I always like to bring in
the Newbie like I want to leave
everybody in even if they've never heard
the podcast or heard about any of us in
any way
um they feel like they're part of the
conversation so we will assume that I
have done that sort of intro
um and then um
yeah I mean otherwise we can get rid of
do you have any questions prior do you
have anything on your mind any uh not
really no I mean I was gonna
talk about like I'm I'm like allowed to
say like you can go to better you care
like.com like the Instagram like you
know things like that that way it's sort
of like hey like if you know if you're
interested like you can check us out
blah blah blah things like that yeah
yeah plug away don't be afraid to say do
anything and like yeah I'm I'm totally
fine and like I said again yesterday if
you like accidentally say something or
something you forgot I can throw in the
description
um I can add it to social media if you
say something you wish you didn't say
just let me know I can clip it out like
it's I control everything on this
luckily so I get to kind of present it
how I'd like and I definitely like I
said I'm like such a fan of you guys and
everything you're doing so like please
plug away on better absolutely well
thank you I'm excited I'm ready to jump
right on in cool all right well everyone
listeners welcome to the junkyard love
podcast I am happy you're here today I'm
here with Megan I'm here with Megan
Hawkins
um
yeah I I want to get into your story
Megan you uh you gave me a glimpse of
your story last night and I was just
mind blown I was just like you
introduced it as you're not gonna
believe this and I'm like okay cool and
then it was it was truly an unbelievable
story
um and then yeah and then just your
journey after that
um I really just want to let you kind of
take it away in a lot of ways because I
feel like you you describe your journey
so well and it leads right into
um everything about about ketamine and
ketamine therapy and kind of like how
you how you guys started this whole
thing and um and then we'll then we'll
just get going into to ketamine therapy
in general and all the benefits for you
know depression and PTSD and anxiety and
and I'm just like so excited about all
this stuff so
um I would love to just start with Megan
who are you and uh how did you get into
all this stuff
yeah so um my name's Megan and uh I am
with a better use psychedelic therapy we
do ketamine currently primarily via
telemedicine but uh hopefully we're
going to be uh opening up or not
hopefully we are actually going to be
opening up a Los Angeles uh headquarters
location here very soon so that's going
to be super exciting
um but what we do primarily is we work
with patients
um with ketamine and we send it to them
uh at home so you receive a brain box
that's got medication a couple of like
other helpful things in there for
example a blood pressure cuff and eye
mask some little heart fun glasses a
journal a couple other things and uh
basically from the very moment that you
first come to our website all the way to
the point of where you're you've been
just kind of getting into you know
maintenance care you are having a
resource you have information you have
content every single step of the way
um so much so to the point where when
you come to our website before even
needing to sign up you can actually just
get on a call and talk to somebody and
they'll give you you know some
information walking through the program
kind of how it works and go through
pricing things like that so we really
have an incredible team that assists you
really throughout that whole process so
um if you ever have questions things you
can always reach out to us and we have a
wonderful team to help yeah I felt
really supported like like right away
everybody that I talked to is really
cool everybody was super willing to like
answer questions and
um yeah I mean it felt like I think
going into it I was like okay you're
doing it out at home it's in the like
alien alienating thing but it didn't
feel like that it definitely I just I'm
just in agreeance from someone who has
done this it's definitely you feel
supported and have all the resources
good good good yeah it's it's that's the
biggest thing and that when we were
first coming to this and figuring out
like okay you know back in 2019
um ketamine the Johnson Johnson they
came up with their own version they
patented it's about half the molecule
that makes up the total molecule of
ketamine and it's it's a nasal spray it
is covered by Insurance
um but it has to be done in clinic and
that is kind of what started this whole
ketamine revolution in a sense with the
at-home models and you know specifically
for depression anxiety as well as PTSD
and um so that's really when you know
back in that day it was about fifteen
hundred dollars for a single IV session
and there was no preparation there was
no post integration it was basically
just you come into a room you have a
couple minutes of have you ever tried
ketamine and have you ever tried
psychedelics like what's your you know
Baseline going into it and then
basically just you know plug you in and
send you off and while for some people
that could be incredibly transformative
and helpful
um if you have never had any experience
of ketamine or psychedelics and you have
no idea what to expect the thing with
psychedelics is that they can be equally
as harmful as they can be beneficial so
it's incredibly important to really not
only prepare people before you go into
that kind of experience of what they're
getting into but also the way we do it
is we make sure that we start people off
very slow so you're essentially dipping
your toe in the water before you know
essentially cannonballing off into that
deep end so you can really get
comfortable let that guard down because
that makes a huge difference in the
treatment as well and so basically like
I said this was back 2019 it was about
fifteen hundred dollars a session and
you know it's well that is it can't be
very beneficial it's just not feasible
and it's not sustainable and most of us
like you know can't even imagine
spending more than a couple hundred
dollars on Mental Health let alone
fifteen hundred dollars for a single
session and so when creating better you
our biggest goals were to really focus
on making this as accessible as possible
but also as affordable as we can so that
not just that one percent of people can
be able to utilize this treatment
um so that's really kind of our goals
with better you've been specifically
kind of what I do
um you know I've been here since you
know day one one of the founders has
been building this everyday piece by
piece for almost about a little over two
years now I would say and
um you know of course it was definitely
much different in the beginning but
we've been you know growing adding new
content expanding of course you know
into more more and more States being
very thoughtful about not expanding too
quickly wanting to ensure that quality
of care that really is like probably our
number one priority is making sure that
each and every single person gets that
level of care and attention that wheel
desire serve because one size does not
fit all nor should it right we're all
individual unique creatures and we
should be treated as such and so that's
really the way that we have structured
our program so that not only when you
first go through it initially
it's a bit more structured but then
after that you can really kind of play
with it and customize it to fit your
needs which is really great
um in terms of what I do with better you
that has kind of shifted a little bit
you know like I said since the beginning
of course you know I was doing you know
wearing all these different hats at the
beginning and then as we've grown and
built out uh the different teams of uh
departments and just different aspects
of the company uh now what I really
primarily work with is uh with patients
each day and I help troubleshoot I
basically help run the support and
retention team so anytime somebody has
an issue they have a question they're
you know they're doing their sessions
and something is not you know they need
help they have questions they're like is
it am I doing this right I don't know
what to expect sort of like you can get
on a call with me and I'll kind of help
you know just ask some baseline
questions to kind of get an idea of
what's going on and based on that I can
give you really help helpful you know
tools advice you know things to try
making those little adjustments to kind
of find that perfect dose but
additionally
um you know if you're wanting to
continue after in the initial first
round
um kind of moving into more of that
maintenance that's also really where I
can kind of help you to understand how
the process works what maintenance looks
like you know in terms of timeline
frequency how often you're doing the
sessions and just really giving helpful
tools and for people to get the most out
of this and really maximize their
sessions so that's sort of what I really
focus on now with patients but uh you
know among a few other things that
that's kind of primarily what I do now
so right right yeah that's how I
initially had met you because I had done
my first initial sessions and then um
you guys have it to where you have a
conversation with one of you over there
and um yeah I mean I felt I feel like I
felt really at ease after our
conversation there was a lot of things
that like I was kind of curious about
and you explained it really well I'm
like oh that makes a lot of sense and I
I really appreciated your perspective on
a lot of those things
um just to like throw in my hat just to
to say you do feel supported through
this stuff I think like the it may be a
little daunting for people to do this
you know at home seems kind of weird in
some senses but as I mean I I actually
like I wouldn't have it any other way I
really like the way that it went and I
felt very supportive
um okay so can you we'll continue on to
with more of your story but
um what is our initial what is the
difference between
um are different so you were saying
maintenance versus our initial dose so
is it four sessions or eight eight
session is is typically the the dose
that people would be
um recommended
so the way that we it works um we worked
you know very closely with the
clinicians and developing our protocols
essentially and so the way that we've
kind of figured it all out is that if
somebody has like if you've been dealing
with something a bit more chronically
let's just say about a year or more
that's really where clinicians will
recommend to get started with the eight
session package and what that means is
essentially it breaks down to doing
about two sessions per week
um that so that's really kind of the
first you know the main package that a
lot of people do get started with the
other is the four session package which
breaks down to doing about one session
per week that's typically if uh you know
whatever it is that you're coming to
this treatment for it's a bit more
recent like something you know within
the past 12 months or so so that's kind
of the way the clinicians will recommend
if you're interested in getting started
kind of in terms of being able to choose
whether you want to do that four session
package or a session package initial for
getting started
one thing to note is that after like the
first month you really want to do it on
much more of a like consistent basis
um meaning like you're kind of doing it
for the schedule
um you're following you know the
guidelines in the portal you're
utilizing the playlists that we have
specifically curated for each of those
sessions and kind of just really
following as close as you can
um you know just through the program and
the member portal uh kind of you know it
walks at you through each step it breaks
down it has different session focuses um
journaling prompts breath work
meditation exercises all kinds of great
things for each time that you're doing a
session so all of that's in there so
know that like I was saying before is
there is content there's information
there are tutorial videos everything in
that member portal we have created
um so you've essentially got all of that
information and tools needed as you're
going through that Journey
um so basically that's kind of the first
month the idea here with ketamine is
that it typically takes and again this
is not a perfect science
um it's kind of just a ballpark it takes
people typically around six to eight
sessions of like at that full dosage so
that you've worked yourself up to
um to really be able to
uh get enough of the medicine of what
it's doing in your brain um it's it
compounds each time that you're doing
sessions really to that point of where
you can get to a full neurobiological
reset which is essentially if you you
know if you think about it I have
analogies for days it's basically like
the full neurobiological reset is like
almost a control alt delete of the hard
drive it's like resetting all of your
systems and establishing like this
newfound Baseline of self from there
which you can then be able to build and
grow and choose the life that you want
and choose to be the person you want
versus having all of these things
controlling you
um and so
some people you know they're they can
literally start to feel some of the
benefits uh within you know maybe the
first session or two other people it can
take much much longer it's it's very
everybody is different like I was saying
is it it's one size does not fit all and
that's the reason we've created our
program in this way so essentially like
if you've been dealing with something
for most of your life let's just say and
um you're coming to this treatment and
you're like okay like I want to get
started like how how long is it going to
take me to start you know feeling better
the biggest thing that I think when it
comes to mental health especially with
ketamine therapy right most people
they're coming to us they're like I have
tried everything I've tried every
different kind of medication therapy
treatment I mean you name it and nothing
is ever really quite you know stuck for
me or worked or you know maybe it did
but it gave me only temporary relief or
it came with a ton of side effects or
you know just it would just Band-Aid is
trying to cover up you know essentially
a gunshot wound which we'll get into
later but um basically the idea is that
as you're going through it it starts
small we tend to focus on the big things
that were coming to this treatment for
you know I'm severely depressed I have
crippling anxiety how do I get rid of
these huge things but the way that in
you know we want that magic pill of
course to just you know happen overnight
and fix us and heal us because we've
been dealing with it for you know a
decent amount of time and we want it to
go away uh but the way that this really
works is it starts off slow and it's the
little things that kind of start
trickling in little by little and those
small things those start compounding
into the bigger and the bigger and the
bigger things so I I say this to
patients probably every single day and
they don't really love it because it was
definitely a hard pill to swallow with
that is that psychedelics they tend to
give us what we need not necessarily
what we want and a lot of the times we
have to go through the things that we
need in order to get to the things that
we want and sometimes the things we want
we might not necessarily be able to see
or know like what it is that we need to
get there we're just so fixated and
focused on the thing that we want but
we're not ready to tackle or handle that
that's why and say for example
traditional talk therapy when they're
you know they bring up the significant
trauma that you experienced and all of a
sudden you can feel yourself like you
know kind of shutting down or like
seizing up or you know your heart starts
pounding and you can feel your stomach
drop and it's just you know anxiety
starts flooding through your body it's
because there's so much that you know
you're just trying to skip to the end
but there's so much in between that
needs to be processed and dealt with and
covered before you're really ready to
kind of face that big thing again and
that's really where ketamine
um is incredible and being able to help
kind of ease that Journey along the way
so it's kind of like
being able to dive into your
subconscious and essentially having
these things being brought up that are
not usually the easiest or most
wonderful things but it allows you to
start processing the information and you
know the the emotions the the thoughts
the feelings everything that's been so
deeply trapped inside of us and it
allows us to do that without that same
emotional charge that we would normally
have and say something like talk therapy
that would keep us from being able to
even start trying to talk about it or
process it we just freeze up and so this
is really kind of it's like quieting
down that you know monkey mind that we
tend to spend the days that our
day-to-days in and it allows us to just
turn that volume down and turn the
volume up of our subconscious and kind
of just really get that great check-in
with you know what's going on inside of
us and you know facing some of these
things and it's really truly a unique
experience but basically that's kind of
how it works so like I said some people
it can happen super fast like they could
start feeling better within maybe you
know a couple of weeks other people it
could take them a few months it's just
it really depends on the person right
like if you think about it it makes
sense if you've been dealing with
something almost your whole life it's
probably going to take a little bit
longer to undo and unlearn all of those
things that the certain way in which you
have been functioning your whole life
having to just all of a sudden start
changing all of that it doesn't happen
overnight so just it kind of makes sense
it happens you know piece by piece but
what you can kind of expect is that in
the beginning it starts off usually
little bits of you know waking up having
more you know increased motivation
having a bit more interest in doing
certain kinds of things that you haven't
had interest in doing in a while
um a lot of people like you know say
they get a ton of clarity in certain
things uh the two biggest ones I would
say that people really start kind of
noticing within maybe the first week or
so maybe first couple of weeks I would
say depending on the person of course
but is usually uh response to triggers
and instead of just immediately reacting
when something happens instead it kind
of will give you that little bit of a
beat or a pause to then be able to
choose how to respond instead of just
reacting that's a huge one people start
noticing in the beginning as well as
that internal self-talk that dialogue
going on in our head it gets to be a
little bit nicer so those are kind of
some of the things that start that's
where it started begins and then it like
I said those small things get to the
bigger and the bigger and the bigger
um yeah I'll just jump in real quick
Megan with with my experience
um I noticed you know the self-talk that
definitely resonates with me like the I
would be on job sites and kind of
noticing that I would be allowing myself
to be myself a lot more often
um is where whereas you know we kind of
get used to it becomes our just regular
running machine of you know being
self-conscious or like over analyzing
every single time we walk away from
conversation we're like I wish I would
have said this and I said this different
blah blah and that could be like very
you know as much as we get used to it it
could be like very defeating and make us
want you know feel small in some sort of
way so I had a little bit of um I
noticed a lot you know really a lot of
freedom over the time
um being able to like just notice that
in conversations I was allowing myself
to be who I was and not being so
self-critical and then um one other
thing that was actually really cool that
this is something that took me a while
to really like sit with and understand
um because I experienced it I had done a
while back I had done uh micro dosing
psilocybin and I had a little bit of
those effects it took me a while to kind
of understand and like correlate them
with what I was feeling after the
ketamine treatment too but
um I had like a lot of suppression of
anger like I didn't allow myself to feel
I was like there's a lot of ways that
I'd be you know a people pleaser and I
really I hate conflict and all this
stuff but it would there'd be legitimate
situations where it's like man like it's
okay to get angry about this it's not
that you need to flip tables and like
you know yell at anybody or anything
like that but there's a way that you
gotta allow that anger to process I
actually noticed after my first session
um I had I was on a job site the next
day that's also something I want to
cover like if we're able to go to work
right afterwards and stuff too not
afterwards but the day after
um but I was on a job site the day after
and there was
you know we could avoid the details but
there was basically this like this guy
that was causing a bunch of us who were
um you know contractors to like be kind
of wasting our day when we didn't need
to be there and uh he was just being
super rude and it kept adding up and
after a while I was like I was able to
kind of like just be straight up with
him and like kind of like cut the BS and
kind of like stand up for myself again I
wasn't yelling at him it's not like like
ketamine makes me mad or something like
it was just me internally my personal
thing was I wasn't allowing anger or
frustration because I'm like I don't I
don't want to get frustrated I want to
be a a clear kind sweet nice person and
and those sorts of things because I had
learned you know in various ways through
my life that that's how you belong and
you don't want to be ostracized and you
don't want to disrupt the flow of
whatever you know these are things that
I didn't know that I was dealing with
was suppression of anger and so um I
basically like was able to kind of Step
Into You know for lack of a less messy
word like my masculine side of myself at
work and kind of stand up for myself and
tell them hey look man like you're
you're being disrespectful to us and we
need to like let's just have this
conversation so I was not only able to
kind of feel anger that I had been
suppressing which caught me off guard I
didn't know that was something that was
going to come up
um but I was also like less
self-critical of myself I didn't walk
away just being really mad at myself
like oh man he didn't see you as sweet
Jake Ryan's like he's not gonna like you
you know it was like it's okay to stand
up for yourself so just as like a caveat
you know or a you know a side step of we
don't always know what's going to come
up I think with this but it's so
interesting to me to like discover and
allow after these things and go okay
that's what I was dealing with cool this
really gave me some space and like you
said you know I'm always talking about
meditation and stuff on here it gives
you the the space between stimulus and
response like so something happens and
you respond to it it gives you like a
little bit of like hmm okay before I
respond to this I have a little bit of
space to like gather myself and respond
and adequately so just like a little bit
of my personal side but um yeah so carry
on let's go with um just because I had
just mentioned it someone did have a
question that they had asked me um about
so we can go to work the next day so we
can like we don't we don't take this
every single day and if you could also
describe why is there a few days in
between why do we do that
yeah absolutely so all great questions
so essentially
um ketamine is an incredibly safe drug
you can take ketamine once a week for
the rest of your life and have no
long-term issues no damage no nothing
it's really boils down to dosage and
frequency so in terms of you know you if
you start of course you know you don't
want to be doing ketamine every day
that's really where there you know it
gets dangerous it can cause issues with
the bladder it can cause you know like
issues with your brain
um it's just it's not good and uh but
that's you don't want to be doing that
so if you'd want to anyway like it's
it's such like I feel like I want that
couple days to like wow that was like
intense I want to you know sit with that
for a second absolutely well that's
that's the other thing too right is is
that uh you want the ketamine you really
want to allow it to kind of work itself
throughout your system and let it do its
thing because
um typically the way it works is um from
whatever it is that you do the session
after about 24 hours after after that's
really when the antidepressant effects
start to Peak and so that's when people
can really start to notice you know some
of those you know just kind of changed
thought patterns or like that little bit
of clarity or just feeling a bit lighter
in a sense even if they can't
necessarily pinpoint exactly what it is
that like they are feeling they just
feel a bit better than they did
um and so it's really important to let
the medicine work itself out
um and so basically with our program you
can either do a session once a week or
twice a week you always want to make
sure let's just say you're doing the
twice a week you want it at the very
bare minimum give yourself at the very
least three to five days between the
sessions that way it allows the medicine
to work itself through your body also
you know it lets your body kind of heal
a little bit up
um and yeah then then that way also
you're not building up the tolerance
very quickly because that's another
thing with ketamine that you know even
if you're doing it you know what but
twice a week or once a week it's one of
the most common things we see is that
tolerance can build up very quickly
um and and that's normal it's just kind
of how the medicine works
um but definitely just you know in terms
of safety we have a lot of safety data
over the past you know few years that
better you has been you know up and
running from just the patients that we
have seen but we also have some other
like I believe trials and places that we
have been collecting and Gathering
safety data from for uh many other years
before we started better use so we have
a lot of information on you know just
the safety and efficacy of it but really
it just it boils down to like I said
that dosage and frequency so making sure
that if you're doing the once a week
program you're doing a session about
every five to seven days if you're doing
it twice a week it's about every three
to five days somewhere around there
um in terms of when you're doing the
session can I go to work afterwards can
I drive afterwards so the answer to all
these things it really heavily depends
on when you're doing the session and
kind of just how you feel how you and
how you respond to it so let's just say
for example that you're doing the
session after work in the evening
typically we recommend people that if
you are going to do that try to do it as
early in the evening as possible because
typically people can kind of fall into
around two camps the first being that
when you come out of the experience
Academy it really kind of turns your
mind on your brain can just feel very
switched on and it can make it a little
bit more challenging to fall asleep or
even stay asleep other people they'll
when they come out of it it can just put
you down and they actually get the best
sleep that they've had in a while so
until you kind of know which one you
fall into
um if you're trying to do it super late
at night
um it's just then it could interrupt you
you know your sleep going into the next
day and then of course if you have
worked that following day being super
groggy you're tired
um in terms of like if you were doing
that session in the evening even if you
did it a bit earlier in the evening
usually I'd say like probably
six seven seven thirtyish latest I mean
it really just depends on what time it
is you typically go to go to bed I
usually will say give yourself at least
like three three and a half hours for
almost from whenever it is you're gonna
start that session to like when you
normally go to bed because that's
typically how long if you're ingesting
the medicine it will take for it to kind
of process through your body
um there's a couple of differences in
terms of side effects feeling things the
next day can I go to work after things
like that so
basically we have two ways that people
do the medicine
um people can either ingest it or they
can spit it out so essentially how it
works is it's an oral trophy or a
lozenge basically choki is kind of a fun
weird word but uh that's the clinical
term you can just call it a law since
that's essentially the same thing
um so they come in these little squares
they are flavored we have a couple
different flavor options available so
trust me that definitely makes the
experience much better
um because you put the medicine in your
mouth and you have to be sitting upright
and you're holding you're basically kind
of biting and chewing down on the little
lozenges you want to get them to
dissolve as quickly as possible and then
essentially once they've completely
disintegrated or dissolved into that
liquid saliva without without swallowing
you're essentially going to be holding
all of that saliva in your mouth like a
chipmunk like
for about 10 15 minutes or so and the
reason for this is that when the the
oral absorption that's primarily where
you're going to be getting these
psychedelic effects from the medicine
it's when you go to actually ingest it
that's where you're going to be getting
more of the analgesic or the pain relief
benefits so for example we have a lot of
patients that are you know have chronic
pain and a lot of the times chronic pain
is accompanied by depression because
that pain takes a humongous mental toll
so we see that very very often but um
basically you know we aren't prescribing
ketamine for chronic pain but it is kind
of almost like a byproduct that can help
that chronic pain a little bit while
it's you know being used for the
treatment of you know the depression or
the anxiety essentially but if you
struggle for chronic with chronic pain
as I do
um then typically those patients will
ingest the medicine after about that
10-15 minutes of holding all of that
saliva in their mouth and um basically
there's a few differences when you
ingest the medicine it is going to first
it's going to make the duration of how
long you're really feeling the effects
of the medicine it's probably going to
make it last a bit longer so typically a
session is somewhere around about 45
minutes to usually somewhere around
maybe an hour and a half that's kind of
like the ballpark window sometimes it's
right at that 45 minute Mark other times
it's you know a little bit longer it
just kind of depends on the day the time
there's a ton of little variables that
go into this but essentially
um if you do ingest it it's probably
going to be a little bit closer to that
hour and a half if you're spitting it
out probably will be closer to about
that 45 minutes to an hour just to give
you kind of an idea now of course not a
perfect science that's just sort of um
that you know Baseline of just
ballparking it pretty much
um so that's the first thing it's gonna
make that session last a bit longer the
second is it's probably gonna make you
feel like you're going a bit deeper into
the experience and the reason for this
is that when you're orally absorbing
that medicine for that 10 15 minutes
you're absorbing about 25 of the total
amount of medicine that you were
prescribed by the clinician so it's when
you go to ingest it you're absorbing
about 10 percent extra which is the
reason why of course you know probably
going to feel a little bit more but now
it's going through your digestive tract
your you know in your stomach being
metabolized so the reason it can make it
last longer is because now you're
getting that second kind of absorption
um but additionally you're also it's
going to be getting processed by the
liver and the kidneys for up until about
three hours so if you ingest us the
medicine after about the like probably
45 minutes to an hour from ingesting it
you can almost get a little bit of a
second wave in a sense so even if you're
not fully under the experience and
you're kind of you know coming out of it
sometimes you can get you know a little
bit of that second wave where you'll
feel you know kind of some of those
effects coming back in a little bit so
the way that we
um well basically that's the second
thing with the ingesting the third thing
uh is that basically
um it can make you a little bit more
susceptible to some of the more not so
wonderful side effects that could
include anything from a bit of increased
nausea to a bit of an upset stomach
um of course you know the prolonged
feeling kind of the effects of the
medicine longer to kind of really return
back to that full Baseline
um as well as some people could get
um a not like a very not wonderful
headache other people the next day could
feel a bit hungover uh it's it's not
guaranteed that any of these things will
happen it's just something that we have
seen everybody's different some people
can ingest you know we prescribe as high
as 800 milligrams per session and we
have some patients that are taking that
full 800 ingesting it and they have zero
side effects at the same time you could
also have somebody that is uh you know
taking what the typical standard doses
that people initially start off with
which is about 400 milligrams
um like that's what is initially
prescribed not initially starting off
with but um we have people that will try
doing the ingesting at 400 and they get
horrible side effects and so we always
in that first month it's really about
playing around with it
um I typically will recommend if people
want to try ingesting to start off doing
that at a lower dose so when you start
we start people off between one to 200
milligrams for the first session that's
really a good training wheels kind of
just you know like I said getting your
feet wet before jumping into the deep
end and getting you comfortable and
familiar and a little side note the
reason that we do this is because
as you know with the IV if somebody has
never had any kind of experience with
ketamine or psychedelics and you know
you you there's naturally a lot of fear
or misconceptions or stigmas things that
have you know you've read or heard about
just you know over the years ketamine
has been around since this the early 60s
so there's just so much you know history
with it and
um you know just negative things that
are associated with it but when you're
first coming to it of course it's
natural to have a bit of anxiety or oh
my gosh like you you're expecting it to
be this whole great big thing that's why
we start you off very very small so you
can really kind of start with those
training wheels and then as soon as you
feel safe and comfortable can be able to
then increase little by little up until
that dosage that the clinician
prescribed you so that's kind of how
that part of it works but essentially
if you're doing the the ingesting method
um typically it just kind of depends if
you're going to try to ingest it I
recommend trying to do that first at
around like the two to three hundred
milligrams just kind of see how you feel
see how you respond if you don't have
any bad side effects by all means you
can absolutely ingest it it's totally
fine it's totally safe uh it's really
just more about personal preference
um you guys also sent um started
interrupting it you guys also said I
forget the name of it it's like a for
your stomach like if you have upset
stomach
yeah yeah so you guys also sent that too
and that seemed to be to be beneficial I
think my first two times I didn't use it
because I'm like I think I'm tough or
something
um but um I was I was honestly fine both
times
um so the first two times I Didn't Do It
um and then after that I ended up I
ended up taking it like just as a little
extra thing and I felt that both times I
was I was totally fine and I think that
my first maybe half times I spit it out
and then the other times I I ingested it
and I didn't really I mean after the
session there's like you do feel like a
little bit nauseous of course like your
motor functions aren't all there so just
even walking to the bathroom is a little
tough that sort of thing
um but just from my personal experience
I I didn't feel any insane side effects
and I was taking
um 400 milligrams was my was my dose for
my trip so just yeah like I said that's
very typical starting dosage that I
would say probably
percent of new patients that get and
they will initially get prescribed to
start off there typically
um the only reason somebody would get
initially starting off or prescribed a
higher dosage would be there are certain
kinds of medications that can interact
with ketamine in the sense not
dangerously it's more in the sense that
um you're they make it so like you're
what it's doing in your brain is you're
not going to be able to feel the full
effects of the ketamine as much just
because it's kind of blocking it that's
things like stimulants like you know any
kind of an ADHD medication caffeine
things like that as well as any kind of
you know benzodiazepines like anxiety
medications sleeping meds
um there's a couple other ones as well
so that's when you're meeting with that
clinician initially they go over that
with you and based on medications that
you're taking previous experience with
ketamine or not they determine um they
essentially customize the dosage that's
going to work the best for you of what
they have determined based on that
appointment is going to work yeah yeah
yeah you do have a good from my
experience you have like a good
conversation back and forth with
somebody um to just kind of like get a
base of what you're where you're at with
all of it what medications you're on so
can you take
um
can you be on ssris and take these and
have good benefits yeah
but or not the scrivato that I mentioned
earlier the FDA approved version of uh
ketamines it's the nasal spray that has
to be done in office typically that is
actually
um done in combination with an oral
antidepressant so
um what I've seen and actually from my
own personal experience when I first
came to ketamine therapy I was on uh you
know antidepressants I was on anxiety
medication you know sleeping medication
just for all the different you know
things that I was dealing with and
through ketamine uh it has helped me to
get off of basically every single thing
that I was on for years and it's an
incredibly common thing you believe it
or not um
they're like I just the reasons I was
taking this medication I just I've dealt
with it it's not a thing like I just I
have more personal strength than like I
know that you know it's it's okay to not
be okay it's not always going to be good
or bad it's just this is life it's the
management of the Ebbs and flows of
things and so it's allowing allowing
people to you know have that freedom of
not always when something happens oh I
have to go you know reach for a pill and
it's that Reliance on an external source
that is that we're relying on to feel a
certain way and that's really what
ketamine is incredible for is it's
trying to help us make the shift from
you know the external to internal to
internal to external and so it's giving
us the tool like with our program it
gives you the tools and you know to
really maximize you know not only just
what the ketamine is doing but
essentially our goal is to make you your
own like pretty much like self-soothe or
self-healer giving you you know your own
therapist in a sense like just kind of
understanding and figuring out that road
map itself
um I did want to jump really quick back
to the the nausea medicine so that is
something
um it's called Zofran or onsenesteron we
send that what to everybody it's
basically it's just it's it it's a
benign medication in your prop you're
not going to feel any effects from it
um it's really more of just a
preventative for any kind of nausea even
if you you know never get nauseous or
anything like that it's just there as
you know to take if you would if you
want so usually we recommend it in the
beginning
um you know some people can get really
really nauseous from this other people
have no issues it's just you don't know
until you try so that is something that
is included with it so I wanted to throw
it in yeah yeah that's great I um
what is your guys's recommendation again
as far as food I remember my first um
400 milligram session I like I was just
because a lot of this is like the prep
work that goes into it it's not just the
trip it's not just the ketamine therapy
like it's the your day your day of the
journaling that you do before
um I really wanted to like be really at
a good state so I like I went and worked
out I went on like a little run at this
at this place I really like in Austin
um I was just like listening to good
content on my phone I just really wanted
to be in this great space one thing I I
also did was I was fasting
um I you know I don't know if you guys
like recommend or not recommended this
is just my own personal thing but um I I
was on like a just like a Shore it was
intermittent so it's probably like 16 to
18 hours of fasting and that was like
one of the more profound beautiful
Blissful like self-love based trips uh
um for me as far as Academy session so
what do you guys normally recommend is
as far as food and do you have you heard
other people talk about being in a
fasted State and having good or bad
benefits at all absolutely so I'm happy
you brought that up because that's um
another thing for like you know when I
was earlier talking about doing sessions
in the evening
um you know and then going into that
next day for work you definitely can go
to work the next day so long as you you
know feel good you don't feel like
you're still under the influence of it
but when you fast there's a few reasons
that we always want you to fast it's we
require
um that you fast for at the very bare
minimum at least
or like three four hours I would say but
prior to doing the session um the first
reason for this is that if you have any
food in your stomach that's you know
kind of being processed it can make you
much more nauseous
um so that's the kind of really the
biggest one first uh the second though
is
um that anything else that's in your
system the ketamine is essentially going
to be kind of fighting with to be
absorbed so it increases your ability
for your body to really absorb the
medicine and so the reason why you
probably had such a profound and
incredible experience was because you
had fasted for that much longer and
there was absolutely nothing in your
body so one thing that I always will
recommend to people
um if say they're doing the sessions
typically in the evening and that you
know that they've done you replicated
the process done everything exactly the
same and they're just you know some
people can be like it started off really
strong and then I kind of started not
feeling as much that's you know it could
be a few things could be you know
tolerance and you know might need to
increase that dosage a little bit
um but a lot of the times it just I'm
like what did you eat that day and
they're like well I had a hamburger for
lunch but I fasted for a few hours I'm
like okay well you know even if you
fasted for you know those few hours
um it's there can still be like little
Remnant bits and pieces that your
stomach is you know trying to break down
so we will always recommend on the day
of the session to eat very clean light
you know leafy greens grains um just you
know nothing too heavy
um additionally we always say that try
to avoid liquids for about two hours
prior if of course we know we're not
saying you can't have anything
um maybe just like you know a couple
little sips of water here and there but
you know don't be chugging a whole drink
of any kind
um reason for this is that ketamine is a
little bit of a diuretic it can kind of
make you feel like you need to pee a bit
more
um and especially like you mentioned
earlier when you know you're coming out
of that session and you're still you
know kind of you know a bit out of it a
bit dizzy it's hard to get to the
bathroom yeah so that's actually that's
I'm happy you brought that up because um
one thing that we do require
um in the beginning especially is that
you need to have a peer monitor there
with you somebody that
um basically their job and their role is
they're not going to be in the same room
as you but pretty much they're going to
be handling everything else happening in
the house so like say if you have pets
or if you have kids or you know whatever
it is they're going to be in charge of
handling everything else and making sure
that you like where you are in you know
the room or whatever it is the dark and
you know quiet space you're doing that
session they're gonna make sure you're
not going to be getting interrupted by
any kind of external Source
um so that's kind of what their role is
so you can really go into that session
because
any sort of like external thing going on
in these sessions it can just pull you
out of it because it's a very internal
Journey inward when you're lying down
you have an eye mask as well as
headphones on so that's kind of really
putting you just like like straight into
this
um you know kind of internal Journey
inward so like if you feel touch if you
feel sound anything like that or
movement uh that can you know just pull
you out of that internal journey into
back that external environment so that's
the role of that peer monitor in that
sense but additionally they're there for
let's just say if in session you get a
little bit nervous or if you just you
want somebody knowing you're not alone
it really can be a very uh calming and
you know helping with the nerves if you
have any nerves but the other biggest
real job of that peer monitor is when
you've come out of the session that if
you need to get up and use the restroom
they're helping you holding you know
your arm they're helping you to the rest
room because really the biggest safety
concern with this is falling and so
that's really kind of the biggest
priority is making sure you do have that
person there with you to help you to the
restroom but the reason also for that uh
you know not having liquids for those
couple hours prior is just because again
you can make you feel like you need to
pee a bit more
um and so our goal is by the time you're
sitting down and starting the session
ideally you won't really need to be
having to get up or do anything for
about an hour and a half to two hours
give or take
um because when you come out of that
session essentially you're not done
you're not just like getting up and you
know going about your day you're going
to be sitting there for at least another
you know 30 45 minutes just you know a
depending on how long you're still
feeling the effects of it but B what we
have you do when you come out of it is
uh we call it the post reflection stage
so essentially you're sitting there you
can either pull out the journal that you
received in the brain box that we send
you and start basically just writing
about your experience whatever came up
for you well you saw how it made you
feel you know whatever it is kind of
just reflecting on that experience now
of course sometimes you can be still
heavily feeling the effects of ketamine
and I can tell you from my own personal
experience trying to sit and write in a
journal coming out of it looked like
kindergartner just scratch it for some
reason it's because it messes with your
your motor functions it's like I just I
could not write to save my life and so
what I recommend for people that if they
experience that is you can you know pull
out your phone and start You Know audio
recording yourself additionally in the
uh the member portal that we have um
it's both a web app as well as we have a
mobile app that you can access
everything directly from your phone so
it's super convenient and it has a
journaling function in there so you can
even you know pull up open that and just
start you know dictating
um you know verbally dictating into that
journaling entry in there if you want
however it is you do it whether it's
physically writing you know speaking or
dictating just so long as you're
reflecting and you know kind of
recording getting that experience out
the reason for that is that you really
want to be able to come back and
re-listen or re-read these experiences
is because you're doing some pre-session
journaling you know there's intentions
there's session focuses
um that we can you know prompt you with
in the portal as you're working through
it
um so the idea is that as you're kind of
working through doing each of your
sessions you're able to really track how
you're feeling going into it how you
feel when you come out of it typically
we'll recommend about maybe the
following day or maybe two days after
you do the session come back to that
journal and re-read what you wrote ask
yourself the question do I still feel
the same if so that's okay maybe there's
a little bit more there that I need to
uncover if not then how do I feel
different and what ways do I feel better
that's really going to help you to kind
of start piecing together the the puzzle
essentially in your journey onto that
that new you is that better you yeah
yeah I mean I will say too from my
experience I feel like you guys did a
really great job at the journal prompts
I really like the journal problems um I
found myself
I mean I I'm I'm a writer in general I
like writing a lot already so maybe it
was like more natural to me but man I
felt like once I started going like you
know you answer the first question and
you're like kind of thinking about it
okay cool and you use you know get some
stuff out and then you keep going I mean
I found myself just lightening fingers
on my keyboard I was like oh I really
like these prompts these are really cool
um so yeah yeah it really did and it was
really cool to like realize how much I
wrote or like allowing myself to feel
those things that that I wrote out um
another thing so this was actually a
question that I had um for
I I forget maybe it was Brendan Brenda I
talked to somebody else yeah yeah so I
talked to him one of my main questions
was okay so this was before my first
session I was like okay so I'm gonna
write this journal prompt stuff you know
this is things that come up maybe I'm
like maybe I am or I am not aware of
these certain things these certain
things that are that are you know
plaguing me inside here's why I'm why
I'm doing this in the first place
um I asked him I'm like so while I'm
under the session am I supposed to
attack these things that I wrote about
am I supposed to try to intentionally
bring those up I was very like curious
about that and he was like no don't
don't worry about it don't try to
control it and um I was I was confused
at first like whoa
how does it make sense that I'm bringing
these things up and then they're getting
solved if I'm like you know like what
basically what does the trip have to do
with these things that are apparently
harming me or you know things that I
Journal about
um and I found that to be very
interesting if you can go to that so
basically like
you know how does how does the stuff
you're journaling about in the trip like
what do those have to do do with each
other I guess even more broadly how the
heck does tripping on ketamine in you
know comfortable safe environment how
does that heal our depression you know
how does that great question so that's
actually believe it or not one of the
biggest things that I would say most
patients struggle with it's the The Art
of Letting Go and so the whole idea with
this is that I'll give you an analogy
for kind of how to essentially you want
to approach the session so before you go
into it the reason we have you doing
that pre-session journaling setting and
attention you know writing out answering
some of those questions is essentially
the idea of what we're trying to do is
we're trying to get whatever it is
that's been going on in your mind
whatever you've been thinking whatever
you've been feeling these are just you
don't absolutely have to use those
things that are in there they're merely
just there as suggestions if you don't
really know where to start like I said
you can really kind of customize this
treatment for what you need but
typically most people are like I've
never drawn on my life like I don't know
where to start like what do I write
about like hi like welcome to my inner
like mind or something right like people
just don't know where to start so that's
why we give you those prompts and those
those tools to utilize if you need a bit
more of that guidance but the idea is
essentially to just whatever it is that
you're feeling I always recommend people
give yourself even if you don't use all
of it give yourself like about a 30
minute window prior to when you're going
to start the session to sit down and you
know write answer some of these Journal
prompts set your intentions clear out
the space in your mind think of your
mind as kind of like a hard drive right
we're trying when your mind when there's
too many different programs or software
or files on the computer it starts short
circuiting it starts overheating it
starts slowing down it's not functioning
or firing properly so the whole idea is
that in order to get the like prepping
the computer to really kind of be able
to work you know and have the software
work efficiently or put like you know
effectively I guess
um as you're trying to clear out some of
that space on the hard drive so you know
that's essentially you know when you're
writing these things out you're getting
it out of your mind so it can live
somewhere else outside of you because
oftentimes when we have all of these
different thoughts and feelings smiling
around inside of us we can't really make
sense as to you know what things connect
or like why I like there's the three
things there's the what why and the
where a lot of the times we'll only have
one or two out of the three but if we
don't have all three of the pieces for
whatever a problem is then that's where
we can start to get you know overwhelmed
trying to figure it out and the best way
for our brains to be able to articulate
what our thoughts and our emotions are
trying to you know say essentially is
really through physically writing with a
pen and paper and I think the reason for
this is that you know when you're when
you're texting or when you're typing on
a computer even just talking you can you
know you're able to do those things much
faster faster you can add fillers you
can kind of tend to you know go off down
rabbit holes as I tend to do often but
when you're physically writing pen to
paper you have you're thinking about
what you're writing every word that
you're writing down you're not just
scribbling down every little thing
because it would take forever to write
all of that so it's it's kind of like a
way of filtering out all of that excess
noise and just really getting out the
true thoughts and feelings that you're
experiencing and so the idea of the
pre-session journaling is to really just
clear your mind clear out that mental
space so you can go into the session
feeling lighter and not having all of
that information kind of circling around
because the more that you're thinking
about it or it's you know you're
experiencing it the harder it's going to
be for you to really be able to
essentially let go and you know not be
you know so kind of just like engulfed
or encompassed in all of that chaos
going on in that monkey mind so the idea
is you know do the journaling get this
stuff out of your mind clear your head
uh one of the most powerful things to do
prior to a session is some you know
light breath work it's incredible for
just clearing out that you know the last
minute things spiraling around your mind
or you know letting go of some some
tension and just kind of shaking out any
little last bits of anxiety it's
incredible just kind of helps you to
drop right into that state you want to
be in going into it so after you do the
journal you've set the intentions the
idea is to let all of it Go clear your
mind take some deep breaths and
essentially just sort of surrender into
the experience so yeah exactly and we
have those few mantras we have you know
the breathe the trust let go and be open
right so trusting or reading of course
connecting to your breath
um you know trust trust the experience
trust yourself trust the medicine uh you
know be um let go let go of any
expectations that you might have
anything that you want to get out of
this anything that you're trying to work
on just letting go of all of that and
then the last being open being open to a
new experience letting whatever it is
gonna have that happens happen and not
closing off from it and so that's kind
of the mantras that we always say to
repeat to yourself before going into it
and so when you then go into the session
this is the analogy I always give to
patients is imagine that you are in a
car and
um essentially the music that you're
listening to these pre-curated playlists
that we have created and all of that is
you know in the so good too they're so
good I love them thank you thank you we
really spent a lot of time making sure
that what we
what we end there
um it's very thoughtful and was going to
be able to deliver a certain kind of
experience
so basically the music aside from the
medicine itself
I would say the music is probably the
most important aspect of the session
because essentially that music is going
to be the driver of the car the music is
responsible for navigating you from
point A to point B getting you from you
know again same thing from point A to
point B so the music is the driver of
the car you essentially want to be the
passenger that's you know sitting in the
car looking out the window hearing the
music and kind of just observing and
experiencing the the journey basically
and not trying to navigate or backseat
drive like oh no you were supposed to
turn left here like you were supposed to
go there and it's like no no like they
got this they got GPS like the music
it's handling it like it's got you
covered you don't need to worry about
this right and so that's a really huge
thing that a lot of people really
struggle with is you know especially
having gone through your entire life
always having to try to be in that
essentially like state of control
so that's really where ketamine is
incredible for helping us with
depression and with anxiety because
oftentimes what happens is when certain
things emotions thoughts just you know
trauma pain when things come up and when
we start dealing with them it makes us
feel like we are out of control because
things we're feeling these things things
are happening we're thinking certain
things that we're like oh my gosh like
what's going on this is too much and uh
like I don't know what's going on with
me right and so that makes us naturally
want to try to control ourselves even
more and push those feelings down and
get back into that seat of control and
so you know especially a lot of you know
kind of type A personalities it's like
this is how I work like when I'm not in
control I freak out and so it's
definitely harder I would say for those
people but it's it's a learned practice
the more that you can get comfortable
and essentially really letting go and
surrendering not trying like letting the
experience kind of take you and show you
what it's trying to show you like I was
if you remember earlier psychedelics
they tend to give us what we need not
necessarily what we want and we have to
allow it to show us and guide us so that
like a lot of the times I'll seriously
be talking to patients and they're like
I was going through this you know a
session and this thing came up and I was
at first you know I was scared or I was
trying to like you know go away for it
or this other thing came up that I had
it was an intention or was something
that I had wanted to come up and I was
trying to like run towards it when I did
that then what started happening is
you're trying to go back in getting into
that conscious mind the whole idea with
these sessions is to quiet down and kind
of separate yourself from that conscious
mind so you can dive into that
subconscious and just see what it's what
you're holding on to what's actually
happening inside of you
um and so that's really where when how
it helps with the depression and anxiety
is that it allows us to let go of that
seat of control realizing that
everything is going to be okay I don't
have to be in control of everything in
order to you know feel a certain way in
fact the more that I am trying to be in
control the less that I am able to
actually get to be my most authentic
self and
um it's trust me it took me some time to
you know kind of really be able to get
to that point but like I said it's
something that gets easier and better
with the more and more practice that you
do so uh definitely definitely something
that people are gonna have some trouble
with but uh we're here to kind of help
you and guide you as you go through the
Journey
yeah huge huge I I mean that was
something for me is like the constant
you know the Mantra of allow except okay
it's fine you know I mean and it's I
feel like that is such an Ultimate key
with all of this because it actually
kind of ends up correlating to the rest
of your life you know where I was
talking about you know I get
self-conscious or I wish I wasn't like
this it's like you are like this it's
okay too you know like you're not an
awful but it doesn't mean this you know
whatever this this allowing I think that
um all the preparation and the you know
with psychedelic therapy psychedelics in
general the biggest thing I mean the you
know science tells us that the
experience tells us this anything that
doesn't even have to do with therapy
anything about psychedelics you what
you'll hear constantly is set and
setting and that is obviously your
environment
um you know your your diet mentally and
and like you know the things you're
listening to that day the um you know
like avoid the news that day that sort
of thing the the environment being set
up in a way and you check all these
boxes and okay I did my journaling
um you know I I made my bed before I
laid in it I'm in a safe space I trust
that I have these two hours I put my
phone in airplane mode nobody's gonna
knock on the door like you set your
environment up to where you can contain
continuously check back in because
sometimes you get you know just to reuse
your your car analogy like sometimes the
music takes you on like a dirt road you
know and you're like oh this is okay is
this and I find myself yeah I find
myself asking like is this too much and
then like I would go back again to like
because you know when you when you're
under the session there is
um you know to some extent some
awareness of your body and these sorts
of things too so I could go check in
okay I'm still in my bed yeah I got the
blindfold on yeah I'm still listening to
music okay I'm gonna trust that these
people like set me up for Success I'm
gonna trust the journaling I did put me
in a safe you know mental environment
um I know I locked the door for sure
before I did this so there's like this
checking in of can I trust this can I
accept this can I allow this yep okay
I'm still good and then you know within
20 seconds you forgot where you were
even just kind of like tensing up about
for it for a minute you know and it's
just it's huge because
I feel like you'll hear it a lot this is
something I used to say often was I'm a
control person I like to be in control
you know I was like the the typical
person who like you go to a restaurant
and like I don't have my back to the
door I don't sit with my back to the
door like those sorts of things and you
you think that you're making your life
better and freeing yourself more by
trying to control it all the time but
there's really a lot of um overlay with
this allowing during the session that
comes into play in in your everyday life
and I found that to be a huge profound
thing for me was this it's okay to not
have control of everything all the time
you're going to be fine allow it accept
it you know so that's that might be
something other people have come up is
this um you know you don't have to
control though oh absolutely one of the
things I love telling people is that you
know the the universe it's got a mind of
its own right it's gonna do its thing no
matter what you like what you try to do
or what you try to control essentially
like all that any of us have any real
control over is is our ourselves the way
that we react the way that we respond to
things anything outside of us we can try
to think or you know trick ourselves
into believing we have control over it
but the reality is is that we have no
control it's you know we're just we're
kidding ourselves into there's freedom
in that too yeah there's so much freedom
and you know it's the idea I have this
um this quote that I really do live by
and that's that I think that in life
it's about 10 of what happens to you and
90 how you react or respond to things
because like I said things are just
gonna happen without you know you could
not have prepared for it there's
absolutely nothing that you could have
done to avoid it or change it just
that's kind of the way of the world
right the world it's got a mind of its
own it's gonna keep on spinning so why
get out and push right it's gonna keep
doing its own thing you don't need to
get out there and be trying to you know
move mountains it's essentially
everything it's have having a trust in
that knowing everything has a reason a
purpose whether we know what that reason
or purpose is in the moment
oftentimes it's the kind of thing where
uh in it's only really in you know
hindsight that you can see that okay the
reason when this happened the reason
that this didn't work out was because
you know down the road I was supposed to
you know do this or go this way and if I
had gone that way I would not have gone
this way and so it's of course in the
moment when we're trying to do something
and it's not working out or you know
experiencing friction
um it's it's of course frustrating and
we're like why isn't this working like
I've put everything into this this is
what I'm supposed to be doing but it's
really just you know kind of accepting
that okay like I might not know the
reason yet but it will reveal itself in
time how much time who knows it could be
you know a day a week could be a couple
of years it's just it's it's about
really trusting that everything
works itself out in some way shape or
form that you know we will be okay and
another thing too I actually wanted to
touch on that I loved that you brought
up is that when you were in that session
and all of a sudden you could kind of
feel some of that little bit of tension
or that anxiety of like oh no no no kind
of bubbling to the surface
um that's a huge thing that we always
will tell people if ever at any point in
a session you feel overwhelmed you feel
nervous you feel like oh my gosh like
this is too much don't ever try to take
the eye mask or the head phones off
really I mean you could take the
headphones off if the music is too much
and just kind of like you know but don't
take that eye mask off the reason for
this is that when you are under the
influence of the medicine of course you
know you're in this whole experience and
it's you know the unnormal but when
you're you're taking that eye mask off
or the headphones you essentially like
what you're trying to do is you're
trying to get back into that normal
where you are comfortable or you're not
experiencing all of this stuff but the
problem is is that because you're still
under the effects of the medicine your
normal is going to be distorted and very
unnormal so that can actually make you
have more anxiety more um you know kind
of worked up and so really you know it's
of course that that's our first Natural
Instinct because we want to just oh my
gosh this is too much like I need to get
out of it but you know it's not like a
VR headset where you take it off and
you're out of the experience right it's
like no this is like you know a medicine
that you have taken you're still under
the effects of it so it's very important
to just be like you know conscious and
aware of that and so the way in which to
do it is if you start feeling that
anxiety coming up in that session is
essentially just connecting to your
breath your breath is going to be your
best anchor for you know kind of
reconnecting to your body remembering
that you know you are safe you are okay
and this is all and this is all
temporary this too shall pass and I'll
usually say you know take one hand put
it over your heart one hand to put it
over your stomach and as long as you can
feel the rise and fall as long as you're
breathing you are safe and you are okay
and um I think that like I've had a lot
of people that I've worked with that
um you know they had a couple of those
sessions where they were really
overwhelmed it was a lot and they were
like oh my gosh like I was kind of
freaking out a little bit and so after
after me getting you know this is kind
of like some of the calls that I get to
do with patients is you know kind of
helping and walking them through these
kind of bits of experiences and what
they've come back to me and they're like
yeah I had something that was coming
back up again a little bit and I tried
that and you know of course in my mind I
was like oh there's no way that's going
to work like just breathing like
everybody tells me to breathe like
that's not gonna make me feel better but
believe it or not just feeling trusting
that you know the medicine trusting that
you are safe you are okay and just
reconnecting to that breath they're like
I was really able to Anchor myself back
knowing that like I was okay you know as
long as I'm breathing I am all right and
they were able to then like you said
after you know maybe a couple of minutes
or so kind of catching that breath
calming back down and they were able to
then you know go on with that that
session and and so that's kind of how uh
you know of course not every session is
always going to be sunshines and
rainbows a lot of the times the things
that we are holding on to you know our
pain our trauma these things it's it's
meant to kind of bring these things to
the surface but like I said it's
allowing you to be able to kind of
confront these things without that same
emotional uh like toll basically so that
doesn't mean that there's not going to
be any kind of emotional toll with it it
just means it's not going to be at the
same level that you know in a normal
setting of just trying to talk about it
where you're not even able to like you
know think about it without completely
like shutting down so that's kind of
like the difference of it's allowing us
to start in real time processing and
working through these things instead of
just kind of it comes up and you know we
Retreat or we back down and so that's
really how it's it's allowing us to face
these things process it work through it
so that we can all of a sudden let go of
it and before three of it right it's if
it's a skeleton in the closet it can
always come back and get us at any time
until you know we've gone in and you
know we've taken a big hammer to the
skeleton and all of a sudden it's in
pieces and bye bye you're gone like
you're you're I don't have to worry
about you anymore
and that is kind of how ketamine therapy
works with that anxiety and the
depression it's it's giving people the
ability to instead of like traditional
antidepressants or you know anxiety
medications or all of these things
they're designed to essentially just
kind of
like turn the volume down on all of
these things that we're experiencing and
it's kind of just like a almost
avoidance mechanism of oh gosh this is
bubbling to the surface okay like let's
quiet that back down and you know avoid
it it's not dealing with it and that's
why people then become Reliant and
dependent on these medications and can
find themselves being on them for you
know many years and are unable to ever
get off of them because as soon as they
start trying to all of those emotions
those things they've been there the
whole time you've just been suppressing
it so now when you start trying to come
off of it naturally you're going to be
like oh my gosh I'm so overwhelmed this
is too much like I can't deal with this
so this is kind of really where it helps
you to actually deal with these things
so that you can let go and move on and
essentially ultimately be free yes yeah
be free indeed that's I love that saying
that's a huge thing that's like you feel
free of the things that you thought you
needed to do or have or hold on into for
so long they become you know I was using
the analogy yesterday when we talked
about like the armor we put on you know
I think a lot of us um whether we have
something we consider trauma or not
through experiences through life through
you know happenstance through
circumstance we we put on these versions
of ourselves we we harden up we shape up
we we put on Armor to protect ourselves
from them ever happening again but
through a lot of this healing real
healing not just like you know putting
it putting a muzzle on something was
that still has teeth there is
um I don't know there's a freedom of
allowing it and allowing it to be there
and the sessions definitely do that I'll
say sorry about the the noise for any
listeners and Megan it sounds like
they're building battle robots outside
of my apartment here
um but so one question that that came up
um I don't know how to word this I hope
I'm not being insensitive by saying it
but it's something that I went through
to um you know even years ago like
before I really
before I had even done it like any sort
of psychedelics or Doven really heavily
into like breath work or um I mean even
like um smoking a lot of cannabis back
in the day
um what do you have to say about people
who are afraid that they might like have
a um like psychological break if they're
afraid that they might like oh this is
the thing like I know I've always been
crazy and this is what's going to push
me over I think that's something we
really alienate ourselves with we think
that we're really alone with that but
the more and more I talk to people the
more and more I really assess my own
experience I think that's a pretty
common thing correct me if I'm wrong but
I don't know if you've heard this from
other people like we're afraid like oh I
can't do psychedelics because it's gonna
like break my mind and I'll never come
back down you know we're afraid of
cutting that tether into into the the
great Abyss so have you have you had
experience um talking with people about
this like well what if I go crazy what
what's your response to that absolutely
that's a huge thing believe it or not
like I said uh the just you know Society
there's been so many horror stories out
there and you know so many things that
they've been trying to you know put into
our minds for years of oh you know
psychedelics they're gonna make you go
crazy and lose your mind but believe it
or not it's it's actually the things
like they got it backwards essentially
the things that they told us are safe
and are going to heal us are making us
go crazy and it's killing us and the
things that they told us were going to
make us lose our minds and go crazy are
the things that are actually healing us
and and helping us so they just they got
it backwards they just you gotta flip
that script and it's the kind of thing
where you know it really what it boils
down to is being open-minded right like
you never know if something is truly
going to work for you or not until you
are open to give it a try right and so
like I have a ton of friends still that
you know we've been doing this for the
basically like past two and a half years
and like I'm like I know that if they
would you know try this that it would
help them astronomically I'm like I
could just I I could feel it like almost
in my bones but it's the kind of thing
where you know you can't push somebody
towards this if they are adamant about
not doing it and they're you know set in
stone you kind of have to allow like
what makes this effective is people need
to kind of come to it on their own and
the way that you can almost you know
kind of get them there a lot of the
times is really just through consumer
and customer education right learning
about what it is you know essentially
changing the you know the associations
the things that you when you hear the
word ketamine you know a couple years
back the first things people's minds
would go to is you know a horse
tranquilizer or you know like just
whatever it was right those are just the
first things and you know now when
people hear it just more much more
commonly people are like oh oh like that
healed like my mom or my brother or like
a cousin or like that you know changed
my life or you know just it's it's a
different Association to things and
that's basically just from knowledge and
understanding and education about it
um I would say that there definitely are
and this is something that is uh it's
screened for when you're first going
through and meeting with the clinician
you know they're asking you they're
essentially getting it's like when you
go to a doctor
um you know for like a checkup or
something they have you fill out all of
that intake paperwork you know answering
you know a bunch of questions giving a
bit of like a medical history it's like
you know establishing care with somebody
that's basically what you fill out a
bunch of paperwork in advance we're
looking at that screening through it and
if you've answered the questions of like
if you have any kind of a history of
um you know like schizophrenia or you
know psychosis or
um certain in certain cases um you know
extreme versions of you you know like
bipolar like just certain kinds of
mental disorders those definitely are
things that are contraindications that
ketamine absolutely could
um you know kind of put somebody over
the edge for so it's something that you
know we will never prescribe like the
clinicians but first we're going through
that first layer going through the
paperwork then when they meet with the
clinician it's kind of like a second
round of ensuring that there is none of
that kind of history and if there is
then you know making sure or clearing it
with whoever their um you know
psychiatric professional is and just
ensuring the safety because the we're
never going to do anything that is going
to like our goal here is to heal not
harm and we're never going to do
anything that could potentially put
somebody in a situation of harm and
um so we screen for that but it's really
more of you know any kind of those sort
of uh you know psychiatric
um you know mental disorders things like
that those are the ones that are a
little bit more like if there is any
real room for concern of It kind of you
know like flipping a switch and then you
know kind of not being able to you know
get back to that stability it's more of
those things I would say
in general if it's you know just
somebody normal that doesn't have a
history of you know any kind of you know
mental disorder in that sense then it
really just is more of a matter of that
kind of getting back to that idea of
control right the idea of losing control
and not knowing what's going on
especially you know in a side of
psychedelic experience that is
terrifying because you're like oh my
gosh like what's gonna happen what's
gonna come up I've worked so hard to you
know keep my demons at bay or you know
like just like avoided this because I'm
afraid of what's gonna happen it's most
of it really is just it's fear right
it's fear of you know the loss of
control or fear of what's gonna happen
like it's you know people like I said
it's you work so hard to have this armor
put on this mask that protects you
essentially from any kind of external
threat and you know not know knowing
essentially that you know maybe even
knowing that sometimes the biggest
threat is actually inside of the armor
it's in our minds and you know that can
be a hard concept I think for a lot of
people to kind of you know to swallow is
that oh like wow like I could put up all
of this armor as much as I want but like
my mind it's you know like I'm still
constantly battling that and there's
only so much I can do so it's you know
it's it's up to each individual person I
think
um you know some people
as much as we would want them to try it
or think that it would help them you
know we can't push them that's going to
do the opposite effect right and so just
making sure that you know if somebody is
interested or if they're curious
um you know then you know give them some
more information but it's you know not
trying to push or pressure people into
doing it because if you do that and they
end up do trying it going into it like
when you were saying earlier the the set
and setting it's not only just the
physical set and setting that you're in
it's the mindset you're in going into it
and if you're going into this feeling
closed off and like this isn't going to
work this is going to be XYZ just like
with any kind of experience in life the
expectations or preconceived notions
that or you know you go into any kind of
experience with is more likely than not
going to be the outcome right if you go
into a show and you're like this is
gonna suck like I hate these people like
I'm not going to have a good time more
often times than not that's probably
going to be you'll find ways to make
that true you know just to reassure
yourself so exactly you're looking for
any little pieces of proof so to speak
to kind of validate your claim of I told
you this wasn't going to work and then
you know kind of just going even so much
further the other way so it's you know
of course we wish everybody in the world
could try at least one ketamine therapy
session I think the world would be a
much different place but uh we just have
to let everybody come to it theirself
and I think that's right yeah and and
like you said I mean you guys do screen
for it I remember the initial um you
guys have you you have someone have a
conversation with us and you go over
like um I think there's like a question
there and and stuff like that so I feel
like you guys do it do a good job at
that um so that's all like that's all
established before this and this is like
maybe if you're if you don't know if you
fall into this bar ballpark I mean it's
worth it's worth a conversation like
maybe you can have a conversation with
somebody from better you and they'll um
you know they'll give you more
reassurance so they'll of them maybe
they'll tell you like maybe this isn't
for you at this time or whatever it is
but it's it's certainly worth the
conversation I will also reiterate you
guys cover all this like so all this I
feel like so far what we've talked about
maybe it seems like a lot like it's like
how am I going to remember all this and
whatever and this is all covered like
this is all part of the it's it's all on
like the portal
um they cover this you have
conversations with people from better
you
um this is like like you don't have to
remember literally any of this this is
just like good information but it's all
covered again in every single session
has like a step-by-step it's like you
click on the thing this is your first
session here's your focus and you just I
mean read it and it tells you exactly
what to do exactly what to think exactly
how to prepare yourself I mean I just
want to reiterate you don't have to
remember this seems like probably a lot
for people who are maybe um wondering
about ketamine therapy but you guys do a
great job of covering all these bases
not giving too much information like
providing all the right you know ins and
out for for all of this
um
yeah so uh okay so I I did want to
um you'll notice my air conditioner
turned on now it's even even more loud
it's probably just distracting to me but
um
the
the sides of you mentioned like
our story you know things that happen to
us they end up in retrospect we can kind
of see how they lead us you know they
kind of lead us to our version of of the
water to drink from in in the end you
know that's been a lot of thing on on
this podcast for me personally
um I wouldn't have this huge mental
health focus and like have these sorts
of conversations if I didn't have the
history that I had you know I had like a
what I would say a turbulent childhood I
had like some tough teenage years and
having to heal all of those things and
having to like learn about all this
stuff on the other side now I'm in a
position where I can speak about these
things freely I can you know heal myself
and talk about it and help other people
I can I'm able to offer this space that
if I hadn't gone through those things I
don't think that that would have that
opportun that opportunity
um and this is like like for your
personal story Megan this is
um I would love to get into that because
you know you are in this position where
when that thing happened here you
probably never saw your yourself here
you know being like a you know a
therapist for ketamine you know so
um
let's explore so like how did you like
why would you need ketamine therapy you
know what what happened in your life to
lead you down to to where you are
absolutely and I sort of like I told you
yesterday I said you know hold on to
your seats because it's definitely uh
very out there it's the last possible
thing you'll probably ever you know
guess just you know by looking at me or
you know hearing me talk it's so you're
like wait hold on what like I need to
hear that one more time so uh I'll try
to you know kind of go through from like
the beginning of sort of what happened
in a little bit of just kind of the
Journey of then what eventually
essentially kind of led me to you know
kind of my like real rock bottom and
then when I found ketamine and kind of
like how it's all sort of come full
circle for me so uh basically uh
your thing
um so basically when I was 19 years old
um I was well so when I was 15 years old
actually I got discovered uh to be a
model and I started getting
um more and more into it getting it was
getting more and more serious
um you know I committed to a bunch of
colleges was good to go
um you know to to Boulder and Colorado
ended up deferring a year and uh was
traveling the world internationally
traveling all over different countries
and
um and then came back home uh to
Southern California in Orange County
which is where I was born and raised
um but was in LA for you know the a few
months just kind of trying to regroup
and you know getting ready to then go
back and start you know traveling much
more and so at that point it was you
know over a year from when I had
initially deferred and I ended up
deciding that you know since this
modeling was really taking off that I
was this was going to be my path this
was going to be what I was gonna do and
so decided to not go to college and um
probably within a couple months of
making that decision and like I said was
you know kind of laying the groundwork
for you know then going back out and
traveling to a whole bunch more places
and like I said the modeling it was
really taking off you know it was like
in New York Fashion Week you know Paris
like London Barcelona Australia it's all
over the place and um so basically when
I was in LA I was at a nightclub and I
hate nightclubs they're not fun you
can't talk to people it's not I don't
really enjoy them but it was a one of my
good friends of the time it was their
birthday and they're like hey you have
to come like you have to celebrate me
and I'm like okay fine so I went with
them and uh basically long story short
uh I got shot in that nightclub there
was a
um I'm not going to mention his name but
there is a very not so good uh like
gangster that just happened to be there
because another person was performing
and it was just the the venue that night
was absolutely insane and uh they were
trying to essentially assassinate this
person I had no idea who he was uh
before this but apparently he was
standing right behind me I mean I didn't
know who he was I wouldn't have
recognized nothing I I didn't even know
he was standing behind me so it was
basically they were trying to
assassinate him and shoot him and uh I
ended up taking a bullet and
um of course when it happened I you know
the I thought they were fireworks going
off like I was so naive I've never heard
of gunshot before like and I was just
like wait what but the chaos and um you
know just the Panic the adrenaline
started coursing through my body and
um so I actually did like I felt some
kind of an initial burning sensation but
I didn't necessarily even realize that I
had been shot until believe it or not I
was in the ambulance so I somehow
managed to get within a few minutes from
when the the gunshots rang out from
inside to the outside I got across the
street and then like on the other side
of the street pretty much and uh it
wasn't until then one of my friend who
bought me out was like it was a little
like circle of blood on your shorts and
I'm like what like fine I probably just
banged into something he's like oh
that's just go get you checked out so
walked me over to one of you know the
cop cars they had all these shotguns
pointing at it of like the the entrance
to the club everybody's having to come
out with their hands out somehow I
avoided all of that I just I got out
immediately and um was waiting for an
ambulance by the cop car and it wasn't
until I was in that ambulance that um
they told me they're like oh we have an
abrasion on the front left hip and I'm
like what does that mean like I don't
know what that means right and I'm like
does that mean like I've been shot and
they didn't say yes and they didn't say
no so of course that Panic naturally
starts to you know kind of roll in a bit
um basically it looked like there was a
little kind of like thing Point like
poking out of the skin on my front left
hip and
um so basically like you know they took
the shorts off they're trying to like
look at it and see what's going on you
know putting me on an IV and at that
point that was when it kind of started
sinking in they're like oh my God like
like I I have been shot like are you
what like just trying to process that
information was you know naturally kind
of just like I don't even know what to
do with that just complete shock still
but that's really when the pain started
coming in so anyways long story short
um the bullet it traveled about eight
inches through my body it entered about
um right above my left hip and it was
very narrow so it like was kind of going
like this all the way through my body
and it missed every single important you
know organ
um it missed my kidneys reproductive
system any like my spine I mean by I'm
talking millimeters if I had been
sitting any different kind of Direction
I Would either be paralyzed quadriplegic
or dead and I I honestly shouldn't be
here today I shouldn't have any kind of
quality of life but the way in which
that it went through me it every single
person in the emergency room was like
you had somebody looking out over like
over you so so it wasn't until like
about a month after this all happened I
was just dealing with the physical
sensations of everything but my mind it
was just too much for my brain to be
able to process and so mentally it was
like you know nothing had happened and
it wasn't until about a month after I
went on uh this show where they made
this like visual Recreation of how the
bullet went through me and how close it
was they did this based on all of the
scans and you know the Imaging they did
and the the emergency room that night
and it wasn't until I saw that that my
mind was like oh my gosh like that is me
like I you know was this close like you
know I shouldn't be here I shouldn't be
alive I shouldn't be able to even you
know walk let alone function and you
know so of course when I saw that that's
really when the downward spiral began
and unfortunately I had I was seeing a
psychiatrist at that time that put me on
like 12 different kinds of medications
all counteracting the side effects from
one another there's probably like eight
to nine months of time like within about
a month or so after getting shot that
like I just don't really remember
because I was on so many different kinds
of medications and then you know of
course dealing with all of that
um you know the modeling it just I I was
in certain ways honestly just kind of
out of my mind a little bit right like I
just didn't know what was up what was
down I couldn't make sense of anything I
didn't know what to do it just kind of
stopped me in my tracks and so I ended
up having to decide about a year after
that okay like I was gonna you know stop
and you know give up modeling just
because I couldn't you know get myself
together and so I then threw myself into
a completely different industry like a
full 180 and uh then kind of was just
distracting myself like in throwing
myself completely in that for the next
like four or five years or so and
um you know it was sort of the thing
where it gave me that purpose back of
some something you know to do to work
towards but then after about like I said
four or five years that kind of started
um you know had a not so great ending at
the same time
um you know had a real like my first
real relationship kind of ending very
poorly and then my idea was essentially
that okay like I'm gonna let the rest of
uh you know 2019 kind of just gonna you
know try to figure out what's next and
then very beginning of 2020 I am gonna
Dive Right In and I'm gonna figure out
what's next then of course we get
coveted and the world shuts down and so
that kind of puts throws a wrench in
everything so then now I end up moving
back with my parents to Orange County so
first it was like I lost my like
professional purpose then like the
Romantic then my last quite a sense of
Freedom since when I had initially moved
away from home so at that point that's
really when I hit my real rock bottom
and I was there
for a pretty good amount of time where I
was just not really doing anything
talking to anybody kind of just watching
TV by myself you know I was like asleep
for most of the day awake for most of
the night just kind of like was really
just not in a good space and uh I was
like that for I probably I'd say like I
don't know maybe six months seven months
eight almost and then kind of started
coming out of it just a little bit
um I had started seeing a therapist and
that kind of seemed to help and all of a
sudden I kind of had this little like
realization that like okay like I need
to you know take responsibility for you
know my life or like this like you know
it's up to me I can't keep blaming
things but I was still you know
definitely struggling so then that's
kind of the point of where I then found
ketamine therapy and I'm not kidding you
within probably the fur it like I said
it definitely took me a few months in
the beginning to really kind of you know
consistently doing like the twice a week
program really breaking up all of the
damaged Pathways in my brains and like
unlearning and undoing all of the things
that you know this all of these
different you know the original Source
the trauma
um like once I hit that Rock Bottom it's
like everything that I had been kind of
avoiding all just came crashing back
down on me on top of all of the other
things that had kind of since occurred
just in me trying to run away from that
initial trauma distracting myself to
these other things so when it all came
crashing down you know it was like that
was real real rock bottom and I
definitely had to kind of get to this
like little bit of a certain level of
like okay like I am gonna choose to get
help like I I can't keep living like
this
um so it was once I made that decision
that I then you know started talking
therapy but then found ketamine therapy
about I'd say maybe like two months or
so after I started seeing that therapist
when I had that okay I need like I'm
choosing me I'm choosing to you know get
help and I don't want to be stuck in
this any longer I can't live like this
and uh that was a really scary time
because I have never in my entire life
ever ever considered harming myself
hurting myself but I got to the point in
my life like I'm just too much of a
chicken like that would never happen I
just couldn't even conceive it but I got
to a point in myself where I was so sad
and in so much internal turmoil that I
could understand the level of pain and
sadness that people get to to the point
where they are thinking about suicide
like thinking that this is my only way
forward and so that is really honestly
what scared me into like okay I need to
do something like this is you know
that's a slippery slow debt slippery
slope down so basically within a couple
of months of starting ketamine therapy
as well and the same combination of
doing the talk therapy all of a sudden I
just I mean don't get me wrong it
definitely still took me a lot of you
know work and you know kind of things
having to process but it was insane the
amount of progress I started making and
just in the amount of time that I had
started it right like it took like I
said those few months to kind of really
get to that uh you know full
neurobiological reset but once I was
able to get there all of a sudden it was
like
I when things would happen or come up
that normally would have you know set me
down you know a spiral that I you know
would then get lost in for a little
while instead it was now like when
things would happen I was able to kind
of deal with it and process it knowing
that I'm going to be okay and in all of
this this whole journey I really kind of
came to realize that and I would say
this to myself you know every day even
though I did not believe it for a while
until the point of you know after a few
months started to believe it and that is
that I'm stronger than I think I am I
can handle more than I thought I could
and I got this it's all it's gonna be
okay it'll all work itself out and also
it's okay to not be okay in fact we
actually have to not be okay sometimes
so that we can be okay and appreciate
those times and
um you know just kind of allowing myself
to similar to you feeling and
experiencing letting this pain in no
matter how much I did it want to deal
with it as soon as I let it in then it
couldn't control me anymore it didn't
have that same power that I was running
from and you know then of course you
know when you know starting better you
that was really when I was able to you
know start you know with the ketamine
and uh have been you know building this
company every single day since and uh
you know of course my roles have changed
as we've been like I said earlier
building and growing more and more but
now to the point of kind of like what I
was mentioning what I do today is I'm
working with patients I'm talking with
them when they are at that Rock Bottom
place in themselves when they're first
coming to this treatment you know for
whatever the reason is whatever their
experiences whatever they've gone
through whatever pain trauma
everybody has a different and unique
experience and what I'm able to do now
and this is kind of how it's come full
circle for me is that I'm able to you
know I I will never pretend I know
exactly what it is that you're going
through what your experience is it's
it's always going to be unique and
individual to yourself but what I do
know is that the ways in which US as
human beings react and respond and try
to deal with and process you know pain
and Trauma and suffering there's a lot
of overlap in the ways in which that we
can feel and that you know things that
we're trying to do and that's really
where I'm able to I would say like find
my way in to connect to people and
letting them know and feel that you're
not alone in what you're going through I
might it might be it's not going to be
of course I'm not going to understand
exactly what you have gone through but
the pain the you know the coping
mechanisms the ways in which you're
trying to you know like just function
there's a lot of overlap there and
that's really where I can reach people
and help them and
um you know kind of just tapping into my
own personal experiences of what I have
gone through remembering what I felt
like and what I did all the way along
and through my journey you know all of
my trials and errors you know trying
this it didn't work or you know just all
of the different things over you know
basically the past I'd say you know nine
years I've been you know learning every
step of the way and I'm never going to
not be learning right this mental health
is a journey not a destination and it's
something that I think that a lot of us
don't tend to remember as often we're
like I just want to you know get here
and then I'll be good it's like no no
like we're constantly you know we're
we're fluid creatures we're constantly
changing and evolving always trying to
be a better version of who we were
yesterday and
um you know it's just it's reminding
people a lot of the times that you know
it's it's so easy to be so hard on
ourselves like why can't I just get it
together like why can't I just be this
or why am I always doing this to myself
and it's you know it's important to
remember that you know it's you have the
only way out is through and you have to
be patient with yourself give yourself
that Grace and you know knowing that
like I said it's okay to not be okay but
I I hopefully I I feel like I do a
pretty good job with it but I the the
biggest thing for people when they are
you know coming to uh to better you when
they're coming to ketamine therapy is
they a lot of people they're like this
is my last chance like this is my Hail
Mary like if this doesn't work like I'm
out of options and you know those people
are the ones they're like I need this to
work like overnight right and those are
typically the people that it takes a bit
longer for and so when they're coming to
me and they're like it's not working
like and they're kind freaking out a
little bit I'm like it's okay just you
know remember you got to take it day at
a time session at a time try not to be
so hard on yourself just take it step at
a time but as long as I can give them
that little glimmer of hope like to see
that light at the end of the tunnel
essentially reaching my hand out and
pulling them up just that tiny little
bit so that they can actually then see
that Horizon that's the Difference Maker
is when people know that like oh like I
it's it's you know it is a bit far away
but I can see it it is possible and
that's the Difference Maker from at
least what I have seen in working with
the you know hundreds of patients that I
have gotten to work with over the past
couple of years and uh it's been truly a
uh it's been a journey I won't lie to
you but uh getting to kind of now see
Full Circle that you know I never would
have wished of course to have you know
been shot at you know such a young age
and um you know just such a pivotal
moment of my life but you know now kind
of coming full circle saying that now I
can take this you know awful thing that
happened to me and use it for good you
know to help others along the way so
that not like you know it wasn't for
nothing essentially it's it's you know
my purpose and I I know that I'm meant
to be doing this so it's it like I said
it took me many many years to kind of
get that reason or like why the modeling
didn't work out or why that other career
didn't work out is because if I those
things had I would not be here now doing
what I'm doing and this is what I'm
meant to do and what I'm you know this
this is this is it's honestly the
greatest and most fulfilling thing and
I'm just so grateful to be here to help
you guys and let you know you're not
alone and it is gonna be okay
yeah yeah it's so profound I mean thank
you again for for just being willing to
share all that stuff like it's got to be
you know with time I'm sure you've
learned how to speak speak about it in a
way that doesn't
um like feel weird or feel uh I feel
like a lot of times when we talk about
this stuff we talk about these things
that happen to us to me when I would
share them like am I lying about this
did that really happen like you'd have
to like allow it
um but it's just like yeah it really is
like it's so important you know what
what you said about being able to help
other people it really creates those
little it's like this it's like this
sheet of thing and there's like these
little holes that you get to like okay I
see you in there because I've made that
hole on the way out so I can see you and
and like you said I I love your
analogies and metaphors of being able to
like reach in and actually access these
people and it helps us again with all of
this stuff we continuously think that
we're we're alone we think that we're
the worst where the we can't get over
this thing that happened it was the
worst thing that happened nobody could
understand but just by you sharing those
sorts of things
um and it really does create an opening
and it allows us to allow those things
that happened with ourselves
um some something that I you know really
a lot of my a lot of my work and like my
I mean almost Obsession like something I
think about a lot because it was so
profound to me is
like the self personality identity
um I mean these are really at like the
core of how do I get better or why am I
thinking this way or what's going on
with me or this pain that happened a lot
of it it all seems to point back to like
the self identity
um the personality structure that we
unknowingly formed to get through these
things
um have you thought I mean
where do you think about this like this
before and after of kind of like
allowing our old self to go you know you
had to like really let go of like I
guess I'm not going to be a model you
know that's that's you know those are
things we have to mourn in themselves
like whether you know and then there's
this in between period of
like you know you're the uh I've heard
it said like the the chapter or the the
chapter between stories or the story
between stories you're like I know that
I'm going in the right direction I know
those things don't serve me any longer
but I haven't like made this new
identity I don't feel I think I'm
leaning towards my purpose whatever the
heck that means you know you're you're
in between and I think there's a way
that we have to
you know mourn in in allow through all
of these processes you know and a lot of
it isn't until retrospect that we could
really allow the morning to take place
and like allow that thing to be let go
to to you know let something new in
um I was talking with a
um I made a little post last week
um about about talking to you on on here
and I just like seeing if anybody has
any questions or inquiries I had one
friend who was talking about
um you know she was in I think like her
late her late third or late 20s and uh
she got diagnosed with cancer and she
had like this like really good job
before and she had her whole life set up
like everything was cool she got
diagnosed with cancer had to go through
all that all this time off work go
through all that turmoil for for a long
time and then you know she got she was
good on the other side they got rid of
the cancer but she tried going back to
that job she tried going back to that
whole life and she was like I don't none
of this makes sense to me like she had
this you know Awakening of a new version
of herself which I think you know facing
being forced to face our our own
mortality in a lot of ways is is a huge
thing in our culture that is you know
massively overlooked and um it really is
you know a lot of our old self has to
die off in a sense um and and so she
kind of inquired about you know if if
ketamine therapy could help with those
sorts of things like being able to to
let an old structure of ourself die off
being able to like really adapt to and
allow to this new side of ourselves and
how to trust that so
um so I love that you shared your story
about you know ketamine allowing this
new version of who you are to to take
place you know
um what do you think about about the
self identity personality structure
um you know in in I guess the death in
in Rebirth of these sorts of things and
and like how does psychedelic therapy
play a role in that I guess too
absolutely that's a great question and
you know first time you know I'm so
sorry that you know your friend had to
go through something as you know in
intense and terrifying as that at such a
young age and you know just as like you
know of course much different you know
being diagnosed with cancer versus you
know getting shot but you know still
both things it's making us aware of our
mortality in a sense and I think that
when you know at you know especially you
know being younger and having something
like that happen because you have so
much life ahead of you it's uh you know
it can at least for me it really rattled
me to my core it made me realize that
like oh like you know I'm not gonna live
forever like I'm not Invincible like I'm
just human and
um you know of course through the you
know just the years of you know just
like the pain and the suffering and um
you know just the trying this trying
that one thing that I realized really
like when I started the ketamine therapy
was that it's not that you have to
essentially let like your old self die
it's more that when kind of looking at
the person that you used to be there can
still be pieces and aspects of that
person that you still like that you
still identify with that you still feel
connected to and those are the pieces
and parts that
um at least for me through ketamine it
was allowing me to be able to see
they're like oh I don't just have to
completely write off you know the person
that I used to be the values the goals
the things that I was working towards
because this was the biggest thing for
me is that having to kind of come to
terms with that I am no longer that
person like this what I have gone
through what I have experienced you know
it is fundamentally changed who I am and
in doing so it has essentially altered
you know it changed my you know my
priorities and you know especially after
something of you know like a near-death
experience or you know diagnosis or
whatever it might might be it really
tends to at least from what I've seen
put a lot of things into perspective of
you know instead of just you know doing
whatever kind of you know job to you
know have a career it's you know I've
seen a lot of people that will then go
into something that is more you know
like fulfilling or like that it it feeds
their soul at least for me that's what
this is is you know getting to help
others and of course you know sometimes
at the end of the day if you know
literally being on calls all day of
course I can be you know exhausted but
my like my internal battery doesn't just
feel constantly drained you know my cup
is still full because it's meaningful
it's fulfilling and it is you know for
me it feels like it's my calling but I I
really I had to kind of come to terms
with that like I I was for a long time
really trying to just like that's like
you know who I used to be and like I
can't be any of the things that you know
I used to be or that I you know used to
want because that's you know like that's
just not where I am now or I'm not doing
that anymore but what I had to kind of
come to realize is that it's
I realized that I'm like like actually
like it reminded me of the the pieces
and parts of myself that I had just kind
of closed off to for such a long time
and I'm like wait but like like in
ketamine I would come out of some
sessions I'm like wait but like I
remember like when I used to do that it
used to make me feel so happier like
like I loved it or like you know just
whatever it was no matter how silly or
strange or whatever it is if it was
something like a piece or a part of
myself that that I liked I was I
realized that it's not all or nothing
that I could take you know the pieces
that I wanted and let go of the pieces
that either you know no longer served me
or that just wasn't aligned with this
new you know essentially just you know
me that I have been you know
continuously growing into and
um you know I've had it would feel like
a lot of different I don't know
lifetimes if you could call it you know
in my you know not too many years you
know I'm almost 30 so it's like I feel
like I've lived like 45 50 years in the
almost 30 years I've been here but um
you know just I've had you know at 30
I've had basically three very big
different you know career shifts so it's
like you know starting over over and
over and over again and I won't lie that
was really hard for me having to start
from scratch after just like oh like I
just did all of this I put in so much
time and energy and work and like this
was my everything it's all I thought
about I sacrificed so much for this and
then when it doesn't pan out of course
it's you know it's it's heartbreaking
it's it's shattering because it's like
oh my gosh like was that all for nothing
but another thing that ketamine therapy
really helped me to also realize is that
while those different avenues that you
know I was doing all they didn't
necessarily pan out in the way that I
thought it would there were still a lot
of you know skills and things that I
learned in those two different you know
careers essentially that I'm able to
still tap into and utilize and what I'm
doing now it's not all for a waste just
you know you can use some of the same
sort of like you know principles or
ideas or you know just you know things
that you've learned of how you worked
that you can bring into whatever it is
you're doing and you know kind of just
you know change it a little bit you know
restructure it like you know take it
apart and be like okay when I was trying
to you know get this done for a deadline
like how would I prioritize like all of
the other things I needed to get done
even though it's not the specific thing
of like what I'm like actually doing
it's a different job or a career I can
still apply those same kind of you know
just either prioritization or you know
organization or just you know thought
processes just whatever it might be you
can still utilize the certain things in
like little ways and bring that into you
know what you're doing next and so it's
kind of like you know the reason that
you know they have us you know go
through school and you're constantly you
know you're going from middle school to
then you know high school and then you
know college it's sort of of like all of
those things it's just kind of like the
next step on the path towards you know
leading you to you know of course then
you know whatever career it is right and
it's sort of like I kind of tried to
think of it in that same sense of like
okay like you know this was like you
know my steps to kind of get to where I
am now right and like a huge part of it
is in this job for me uh you know
there's it's it's medical right so you
know we're talking about very serious
things and you know needing to have that
level of professionalism and
um basically like what I did after
modeling I went into mortgage real
estate was doing residential loans so I
was dealing with you know a lot of uh
you know Professionals in a much more
serious environment whereas modeling you
know it's a lot more uh you know fluid
creativity and just you know kind of
characters I would say so like but at
the same time you know in modeling and
working with people from all over the
world all different you know ethnicities
racist is and you know just all of the
things and learning how to kind of find
that way to you know connect with any
different kind of person so that's kind
of what I took from the modeling and
then with real estate you know kind of
taking that you know much more
professional uh you know demeanor and
being able to handle much more you know
sensitive things like you know talking
to somebody and going over their
finances and like just you know personal
sensitive things
um you know and like kind of also
helping people going through that
emotional process of real estate and
Loans that's a huge part of it as well
but
um just I took pieces from each thing
and now incorporate that into what I do
now and so it's I'm like it's not a
waste it's it wasn't of course the the
plan but that's okay and you know we
never want to have to start over again
but you know it's who knows maybe the
reason that you know if we can't make
sense of it right now maybe one it was
she was doing before no matter how much
she tried or wanted it to it wasn't
meant to be and who knows maybe the next
most incredible thing is right around
the corner and uh it's it's just waiting
for you and because you're not doing
this you're able to jump into that and
it's kind of the way that I try to think
about it and definitely helps I would
say yeah yeah I seriously love that you
went this way with that like I like so
cool because I think that's so important
is a lot of times we do feel the need to
like even hearing my own language you
know we feel the need to like reject our
old self or like completely deny it or
you know there's there's if we're going
through a lot of change and we're you
know forming a new version of our
identity I feel like there's
um
you know especially I think when it
comes in kind of like the the mystical
spiritual realm of things it's really
easy to you know we have these things
called ego death and then we like reject
everything about it like I don't have an
ego anymore for a while or we have like
a like just shame about who we were
before or whatever but it's all LED you
to to who you were and I think
um
um you know in in my own Journey that's
been a huge thing for me as there was a
long time where
um when I first got into you know
meditation and breath work and yoga I
was doing it like
like every day of the week for multiple
hours and so I almost got like very um
like cold and dry and like anything that
wasn't spiritual or meditative I just
rejected I remember for a while
um I like I wouldn't listen to anything
that was like funny or like making fun
of anything or um you know comedy of any
sorts when before I loved to laugh I
loved I loved comedy I liked you know
romantic comedy stand-up comedy like all
I just I loved laughter and there was a
long time where I rejected anything that
wasn't like spiritual or Divine or
whatever and then I had to realize that
um you know I had some things some
things happen and I remember like being
weirded out at how dry and just serious
I was like you know like someone close
to me would like had passed away and I
was like just well that's the way of
life you know accepting it like I
wouldn't let myself feel these actual
human human things and um there was a it
was just like a revamping of of allowing
those things in and and allowing
yourself to be you know pieces of pieces
of who you were there's a there's a line
that I've written the ego
the ego doesn't like change nor grit but
loves to fill with hold so there's like
pieces of your old self that you have to
like you don't you don't destroy them
you don't try to like delete these these
you know parts of your life that happen
they happen and they are who you are
today in a lot of sense that are only
who you are today but you have to allow
them I really like that you mentioned
that because there is a lot of um
I don't know a lot of times there's
there's almost like shame that could
that could sneak in I think when we're
trying to redevelop our you know new
version of who we are now and and where
we're at in in life and in work and
romantic relationships all of it like we
we feel the need sometimes I think to
like not allow any of the old stuff in
and I I don't think that that's as
healthy as it could be like now I I mean
I love comedy I listen to comedy
podcasts all the time every Monday at 8
pm is like my favorite time of the whole
week because it's a new podcast comes
out that I love it's a comedy podcast
um so yeah I I I really like where you
went with that I thank you for that like
it is um
forming these new versions of ourselves
doesn't mean we need to reject
everything about about the past you know
there's a lot of good juicy stuff that
we've learned through our lifetime that
we don't need to just throw overboard
you know I think that's good I think
about it like this right like when you
get a computer when you first get it
it's running properly it's running
efficiently there's not too much excess
software on there it's doing pretty good
right and then all of a sudden as you
know you you have it for a bit longer
you're like oh like I need to do this or
that and so you know you start adding
some new software or downloading files
or you know like whatever it is adding
new things to the to the computer and uh
you know sometimes while we are adding a
program or a new software there is a
reason for that there's a purpose it's
designed to like either help or you know
do XYZ but sometimes what we don't
really realize or know is that sometimes
some of these programs or the software
can have little bugs or viruses that we
can't see when we're downloading it we
only then realize it once we're then
starting you know to try to you know do
something else and now all of a sudden
the computer is it's you know that same
analogy from before it's it's slowing
down it's it's overheating is it's not
working as properly you're getting the
endless rainbow wheel that never ends
and you're like oh my gosh why is this
happening right and um so what you do is
you know you when when that happens you
don't just throw the computer away it's
still a good piece of Machinery the
computer itself is not broken it's just
the the files the the software the
programs on it I've just introduced
these viruses and these bugs that is
then messing with the whole functioning
of the computer so like I said you don't
throw the computer away you either you
just you know wipe the like you get rid
of the like the the bad you clear out
the you know the viruses or the bugs or
you update the software essentially
right so it's sort of like you know
Apple if you have an iPhone you get new
updates you know every couple of months
right it's learning from the bugs and
the viruses from the previous versions
of the software that's how it continues
to improve and work better and better
and better so it's the same kind of idea
with you know our ourselves of who we
are as human beings as we grow as we
learn as we evolve it's it's you know
it's such an easy thing to when you're
making a radical shift and going through
a humongous change or a trauma that we
feel that we have to completely like you
said get rid of all of the old so that
we can you know essentially kind of jump
into this new and be this thing because
that's the only way we feel that we can
survive but it's really that you know
it's human beings are greatest
superpower is learning from past
mistakes and experience right it goes
back to you know like caveman days right
like if it's the it's how the brain
works when something happens and the way
like that whatever happens we learn from
that so that when it happens again uh we
know what to do and can fall back on
that you know memory you're that
experience right so it's like in the
caveman days if somebody was like oh
pretty lion and then all of a sudden the
lion comes and you know bites your arm
off you're like okay maybe don't go up
to try and pet the lion again right it's
it's our survival instincts that's our
greatest superpower but it's also it can
be our greatest weakness right it's it's
all about making that superpower work
for you not against you and the way of
doing that is by not you know completely
shutting off the past it's taking the
the you know things that didn't
necessarily work out or that was you
know causing problems or causing the
computer to overheat and it's altering
it it's taking those pieces that did
work and that were good and it's getting
rid of the parts that were you know
making it slow down or not work well and
uh you know so it's just essentially
it's like that consistent software
update and again like you're not
throwing the computer away the computer
is fine there was just some bugs and
viruses you had to clear out and then
update so then now all of a sudden it's
working perfectly again right
essentially same thing as you know what
I was talking about before of going into
these sessions of clearing out you know
your mind just getting everything
outside of your self so it can live
outside of you and it's kind of like
that same idea but there's only so much
uh you know memory or hard drive space
on a computer if you have too much on
there it's just it's not going to be
able it's going to be super slow it's
going to be constantly overworked and
overheated so you gotta get it out of
the computer like whether it's you know
deleting old files or downloading things
onto a thumb drive like you know putting
it into the cloud whatever analogy you
want to put there it's it's getting it
off of the hard drive clearing that
space so that it could be able to work
properly and it's it's one of the first
analogies believe it or not that I kind
of came up with after first starting
with ketamine therapy and I've really
found that in a lot of the different
ways when I was trying to like
articulate and understand what it was
that I was experiencing the changes that
started happening inside of me of just
like you know the way that I was
thinking the way I was approaching
certain things and like how I was
actually growing the way that I just my
mind made sense of things is through
analogies and that was kind of really
how not only I was able to kind of
understand
more like what was going on inside of
myself but I then also found that that
was a really great way for me to be able
to like I was talking about earlier
reach and connect with those people
explaining these kind of harder to
understand Concepts and ideas and
putting it into very simple language
that anybody could understand and it's
just it was the way my mind kind of
started making sense of things and
putting the you know puzzle pieces back
together and uh I find that if you can
in your own ways as you're experiencing
things and going through things the more
that you write it's the greatest tool
that you can use in terms of
understanding what it is that you're
going through and experiencing and it's
actually this is a quote I got from an
Apple TV show physical it's a hilarious
show but there was this great quote in
it and it was that when you write things
down you can't forget and if you can't
forget or no it you write things down
um what was it it was like you write
things down
um so you can't forget and if you can't
forget then you'll remember and uh so
it's the kind of thing where when we're
going through our own Journeys typically
we can kind of tend to overlook the
little wins the little progresses that
we're making or those little changes
that you might not pay too much
attention to unless given attention to
it but then all of a sudden we can
really start to see our progress and if
we ever have you know setbacks being
able to come back and re-read these
previous journal entries of our journey
and going like okay like you know yeah
this is a bit of a setback but like look
at how far I've come from when I started
like I didn't remember or realize you
know like how where this was when I
started right or actually how far I've
really come and it's a great way to
remind yourself giving yourself like
that credit of that you know you are
changing you are evolving it's gonna
take some time but in the end it's it's
worth it and it's you know most people
don't like journaling they're like it's
a chore I have to do it I'm not I'm not
gonna do that but I'm telling you it
really is the the greatest tool that
helped me along my journey in getting to
where I was and just making sense of
everything so yeah yeah absolutely man
it really is like a it's a superpower a
lot of times I like to say that I
I have a lot going on and sometimes it's
bouncing around inside my skull and I
think that I'm going to solve problems
by just looping the same like craziness
that's in my school yeah getting it out
you know in in like you mentioned too
like even just pulling up a voice
recorder and just speaking maybe you're
not even going to show anybody maybe
you're not even wanting to listen to it
ever again but just speaking it out and
talking about it you know talking into
your phone or or ride it out a lot of
times once you get started with writing
the initial sitting down like what am I
going to write about
um I think we're also we're also kind of
trained in the Western World to to be
graded on everything like we we're
riding as if someone else is going to
read it or as if we can write it wrong
there's no writing it wrong when we're
just sharing our thoughts getting them
on paper so we can actually think think
through them I think um Jordan Peterson
a lot of times has some way of saying
like we don't know what we're what we're
we don't know what we're thinking until
we think it you know and and a lot of
times we think that we have this
we have this like string of mess in
there sometimes and we think that that's
okay well I did my best but a lot of
times when you write it out you can see
oh this is a mess I can think about this
a little bit differently so
um yeah I love all of your analogies and
metaphors and everything they're so
perfect there's like I'm just just
saying yes I love the it's also funny
how we're how we're able to understand
you know computers in ourself like it
really is a way of kind of laying out
the the inner workings of our one of my
better ones that's for sure I will say
it's it hit it on the head so like I've
said that people they're like that's a
great way of phrasing it like now that I
think of it they swim like it makes me
see it in a whole new light I'm like
that's the idea right like it just
dumped on me at one point I'm like oh my
gosh like it's actually so much simpler
to like like it gives me like a road map
of like okay like rather than trying to
make sense of everything of like how do
I fix this or what do I do it's like
okay think of it in a very simple
analogy how do you fix a computer you
debug it you delete some extra files you
don't need anymore and you clear out the
space you get it working again it's like
okay like that gives me an idea like how
do I now apply that to myself what's the
excess stuff that I'm thinking about
that I'm feeling get it out of me
download it off that hard drive what are
the the habits what are the you know the
the daily routines that I do what's
serving me what's not serving me what's
helping me what's getting me closer
making me feel more aligned to myself
right it's like those are the programs
that's the software right our habits our
routines that's how we go through life
right it's like that consistency and so
it's just like finding those analogies
that you align with that that makes
sense to you of kind of what you're
experiencing and then kind of use that
almost as like your like road map or
navigation for however you fix or you
solve you know that equation and apply
that to the situation that you're
dealing with and I find that really
makes it a lot easier than like you know
a lot of the self-help books out there
that's like okay you gotta map out this
then you gotta figure this out and
you're just like oh my gosh this is so
much like I don't know where to begin
like it's too overwhelming and you
almost just don't even want to start so
it's like just start small piece by
piece and you know it'll get more and
more and more and that's really just
it's you start by starting that's that's
really the biggest thing is you just
gotta start somewhere step one take step
one one day or day one right hey there
you go
um okay uh we are getting up here in
time
um I I I wanna
um I have pretty much it just one one
more question
um and then I would love for you to just
give us one more summary of of better
you where we can go like how people you
know get started with it what the next
step is after like maybe the this
podcast is the first time they've heard
anything about the even psychedelics
like let's say from from that point so
like where do we go but before we get
into that um I did have a question about
the future of
um like psychedelic therapy the future
of um uh
you know like like job wise I I had one
friend who I'm like I'm I'm listening
loud and clear too you know I'm
interested even for myself like if we're
seeing maybe in the future
um as this world opens up and it's like
really actually helping people you know
normally we have the routes of you know
you go to school and you become a
psychologist and or you you know even
like a school counselor or whatever it
is how you can help people I think
there's a lot of people who listen to
the podcast who
um are kind of like we know that we want
to help people and we're not really sure
how and I think that like for me
personally like the it's this stuff is
super enticing like if I could you know
help people out and you know help people
go through Academy therapy so the future
of like work in the Psychedelic field
like not only just for better you but
like I don't know I guess where do you
see like 15 20 years down the road like
what's this going to look like how could
someone who's listening who has interest
like prepare themselves or lean into it
or who do we reach out to any of that
stuff and then um if you'll just make
sure we know exactly where to go for
better you to further ourselves with
other you better you absolutely great
question so a lot of exciting things in
the pipeline in terms of the world of
psychedelics So currently at the moment
the only legal psychedelic is ketamine
and ketamine actually is technically not
even necessarily really a psychedelic
it's actually technically classified as
a disassociative anesthetic but when
given at sub anesthetic level doses uh
that's really where you can get the the
Psychedelic experience because like
Traditional Academy was uh synthesized
to be
um you know an anesthetic for like for
surgery or you know it was used on like
the battlefields
um and so it wasn't really actually
until they you know people were coming
out of surgeries and they started having
these crazy mental health benefits that
that's when they really started looking
into it for the mental health side of
things so
um that's basically the only reason
excuse me why ketamine really is the
only legal psychedelic because Tech
frankly it's actually not really a
psychedelic for what it was intended
purpose was when originally synthesized
um so that's essentially kind of the
world of ketamine in terms of other
psychedelics I don't know the exact
timeline on all of them because they're
you know they're always kind of changing
there's a lot of clinical trials and
things that you know has to kind of take
place and that they all have to go
through before they can be cleared and
um you know federally approved but
um like for example
um they've been doing a ton a ton of
clinical trials with MDMA for uh for
PTSD they've been working a lot with
veterans like you know with maps they've
been uh you know researching this and
you know doing all kinds of things for
almost I think like the past 50 years
right like Rick doblin has led the the
way for this and um you know it's it's
they're almost there I think they're in
like the stage three of clinical trials
like like they're probably within maybe
the next I don't know a couple of years
or so that can be approved for uh for
you know PTSD and then as well as
um you know there's uh LSD for for
Alzheimer's we're seeing amazing results
in that regard again all things clinical
trials they're still illegal but they
are you know of course for clinical
studies and trials and things like that
that's kind of where they're Gathering
that data there's a lot of Hoops that
kind of have to be jumped through before
anything can kind of come out so I mean
that's probably you know maybe five
years or so I'll give or take I don't
know the exact timeline again that's
also very fluid constantly changing it
just kind of depends
um I don't know I know like psilocybin
has been decriminalized in a couple of
States I think like Oregon and uh
somewhere else I'm not can't remember
exactly but
um it doesn't mean that it's it's still
technically
um like illegal right like you can't be
you know like selling it or doing
anything like that it's just been
decriminalized
um but so that I don't remember the
exact timeline on that but probably
within the next like I don't know a
couple of years to maybe like six seven
eight years or so a lot of these
different kind of psychedelics that you
know have been around for a very long
time
um you know as soon as they've you know
made their way through all of the
clinical trials and studies and they've
got gathered the data basically what we
think is probably gonna like how It's
Gonna Roll Out is that all of these
things you know it's you have to do in
in clinic in office essentially for any
kind of these experiences which is still
you know even once these other uh
compounds are available or you know are
legal essentially
um you know for for treatment basically
it's still you have to go in office and
that's what makes ketamines such a
um you know a game changer is being able
to do this from the comfort of your own
home it's normally in mental health we
don't see numbers of success rates above
like
30 if like on on the best day like
absolute best somewhere around 30 that's
typically like the success rate with
typical uh you know mental health uh you
know medications treatment whatever it
is the numbers that we have been seeing
from this at home model is I mean we're
probably somewhere of like 80 to you
know mid 90 success rate which is insane
to even think about right it's like oh
my gosh like this this this works right
and people are able to you know
especially if they're in like a rural
area or something and they're able to
get access to you know utilize this
treatment right ship to the home now of
course a lot of the reasons of why we've
been able to do this has been because of
you know covid and telemedicine laws
changing
um and so that's kind of how we've been
able to do a lot of this now that being
said the laws are still probably
potentially going to be uh you know
changing a little bit probably maybe by
the end of this year um they could
extend it again we're just we don't know
until we get that guidance but
essentially from what I understand the
only change that's going to happen is
that you'll have to go in and like meet
with the clinician for your initial
appointment versus being able to do that
through telemedicine as we currently
have been but then after that same thing
you know the medicine everything will be
getting shipped to the home and can
utilize the treatment from the comfort
of your own home so in terms of like
psychedelics that's kind of like the
idea of timing of that you know these
things are in the pipeline they are in
the works they've been you know getting
studied you know trials
um for for a long time we're still of
course you know little ways out but
basically it's you know once the FDA
approves these things then they they
will give guidance as to like how and
who can be able to start you know
administering and you know having making
this accessible so essentially like in
terms of the workforce like right now
um you know it's this is a brand new
industry right we're essentially forging
the path of a brand new
um you know industry that as you know
it's just everything is new right we
don't have a like a Playbook of okay
like you know if you're trying to you
know like open a bank or you know open a
real estate office like you know do you
know x y z and then that's how you you
know this is the the game plan here but
this we're figuring it out as we go
right we're trying to be very conscious
of not doing you know anything that is
going to you know harm but we're really
trying to change the standard of care
and mental health and you know changing
the stigmas that are associated with
mental health and like I was said a few
times in this podcast now it's okay to
not be okay and you know just getting
rid of all of the negative associations
that mental health has had for such a
long time primarily just because most of
the mental health things for the past
you know 50 years they haven't really
worked that well right it's LED people
to you know chronic dependence on
medications and you know suicide and
depression and just not being able to
actually heal and the biggest difference
with psychedelics is that these things
have the power to actually heal and
Allah allow you to free yourself from
the the pain and the suffering you know
that that had been plaguing you for how
like most of your life or however long
it was and knowing that it's possible
that honestly is the biggest difference
but in terms of like the workforce
um you know it's we're trying to be
especially just you know with better you
we're being very mindful of not opening
you know too quickly we're not oh just
we could have very easily like a lot of
our competitors out there they went and
you know they raised a lot of of money
initially and you know they opened up in
all these places but it's you know we
could have easily done that but instead
we're like we want to go slow figure out
the best way of What patients actually
realistically need to maximize you know
the results and get the most out of this
and we realize that it's the level of
care and attention it's being able if
you need help being able to call
somebody text somebody get a hold of
somebody on the phone have a video call
have support along the way guidance
information and just having everything
you need in order to do that it requires
a lot of different aspects and so that's
kind of you know a couple of different
things you know it could be your you you
want to do something that is helping
people but maybe you're not the best at
you know talking to people or whatever
it is but you're really good at you know
systems and softwares there could be the
Avenue of you know being on you know
like the care coordination teams or like
you know the the support like handling
you know the operations of things the
people that actually keep these you know
keep make this company go you know full
circle and keep it running
um you know so there's uh there's app
um you know there's opportunities in
that kind of an aspect as well as let's
just say you're like I'm not that good
at systems but like I really know how to
talk to people I have you know my own
experiences that I've gone through and
you know like I've learned a lot I have
a lot of wisdom you know whatever it is
that could be the kind of Realm of more
of say something like an integration
guide which is
um another aspect of our company is like
what we do is after like when people
first come to us they have an intro call
just to learn more information that
second step then is they meet with the
clinician clinician determines they are
a good candidate for treatment will
prescribe medicine and then as soon as
they receive their box in the mail you
schedule a treatment preparation call
with you know someone from our team they
essentially walk you through how to take
the medication the steps the process
kind of just everything you need to know
preparing you before you even start with
the medicine then after you have you
know started with the medicine you start
slow you work your way up from those
acclimation doses then after you've
completed it's usually after about every
like third or seventh session like
depending on which package you initially
signed up for
um but typically it's about every like
three or four sessions you do that's
when you would then at that point
schedule an appointment with one of our
integration guides and essentially what
their role is is they you know they get
on a video call with you and you know
they kind of everything that you have
that's kind of come for you so far that
you know you've journaled that you've
experienced just everything that has
been happening for you so far they
really help you to just kind of hold
space and like you can either you know
kind of share what's been happening and
then they can kind of give you some
helpful tips and tricks to really bring
that and incorporate that you know and
integrate it really into your everyday
life so that you can actually make those
lasting changes or additionally
um you know they could you know they can
give you you know some more helpful you
know pieces of advice or you know tips
or tricks it's it's you know up to
whatever it is that you want out of that
session essentially and then
additionally if at any point throughout
the whole process basically if you need
help if you need to troubleshoot
something you can always you know like
this is what I do right is you can get
on a video call with myself or anybody
else from my team and we can kind of you
know just help you with if it's an issue
with the medicine if you aren't sure how
like like Continued Care or maintenance
works and so essentially that's kind of
the process from when initially getting
started as a patient all the way till
once you've kind of completed that whole
first round which is it's about a month
is like each round of treatment whether
you're doing either the four or the
eight session package as I mentioned
before you are either doing a session
once or twice a week so depending on
that it varies a little bit but pretty
much like the steps of like how many
different appointments and touch points
that you get throughout the process
um as well as you know you're getting
check-ins you have the portal to kind of
follow through everything you've got
every single thing laid out for you so
as uh Jacob said earlier don't worry you
don't have to remember all the stuff
we've covered it's it's all very laid
out clearly in that portal for you so
um basically after that first month
that's typically where people will get
on you know say another call with me and
they're like hey like you know like I'm
feeling good but like like how does
Continued Care work like do I like am I
done do I still do I need to do more
like I just I don't really know how this
works or what I'm supposed to be doing
and that's usually where I'll just be
able to have a conversation kind of just
to assess how you're feeling where
you're at how much how much progress
you've made and
um you know it's it's really it's up to
you right and the other thing too is
let's just say you initially sign up
with you know the eight sessions that
doesn't mean you have to always do that
you can always go down to the four
session and that's actually kind of part
of the idea is we want to get you to you
know in the beginning you kind of start
doing it much more frequently
um and then kind of as you start moving
forward and you know getting to that
that neurobiological reset then it kind
of gets into more of that maintenance so
it's like okay I started with twice a
week then once a week then once every
other week once a month then all the way
almost to as needed and it's kind of
it's great because you know one per
person might need to do this another
person might need that and So based on
where you're at and how you're doing we
can help you to kind of give you
um you know like a guide map of like
okay like what are your goals what are
you trying to accomplish like how do you
feel like you know asking you questions
kind of just determining like where you
are how much progress you've made and
we'll be able we're never going to try
to you know push like hey like you need
to do another round like or you're not
going to get better it's more that like
hey like if you're interested you can
give you the information kind of give
you just like what we have seen you know
with previous experience and then kind
of just go from there but ultimately
it's up to you and you can always like
you you could even stop for a few months
and come back to us right like I have
patients that like I took a three-month
break and they come back to us and it's
literally as simple as like just picking
which package they want to do confirming
the dosage and then getting you know
collecting payment and sending that
refill in so it's a super easy process
to pick back up after you've already
established that care
in terms of where to go to find out more
information
you can go to
www.better you just the letter U
care.com and you can also go to our
Instagram which is better you same thing
just the letter U care uh and that's on
Instagram
we've got a lot of great content patient
testimonials
um you know just we've done a lot of
conferences activations all kinds of
great things that you can check all that
out on the Instagram page
um and we're always adding new awesome
content and uh you know just great
recommendations for things so in terms
of you know Workforce with better you
those are the kind of different Avenues
in that sense as well as you know as the
markets and things change there could be
more opportunities also in you know
becoming you know like an integration
guide or a like a facilitator right for
some of these experiences it's until
these things kind of come through in the
pipeline we just don't know exactly what
it's going to look like yet but it's
something to you know if you're
interested can follow but Additionally
you know if you're interested in you
know working with you know ketamine now
or you know in any kind of a different
aspect
um you know there's there's lots of
opportunities and lots of different ways
to get involved and to contribute
um so it's you know again like one of
the great things is that currently we're
doing a lot it's all very remote right
so you're able to uh you know help
people from you know the comfort of your
own home until the point of plan you
know of course we're going to be opening
up our first brick and mortar here in
Los Angeles like our first you know
mental health or like wellness center
basically where we can be able to be
doing you know IVs and IMS and having
like little integration pod rooms and
people can come in and you know meet
with the doctor they can come in and you
know meet with a you know talk therapist
just like all kinds of things as well as
um some fun stuff we've got coming in
the pipeline is is that we're going to
be doing some regenerative Health Sexual
Health couples therapy all kinds of
really really exciting us of course you
know with talk therapy as well a lot of
exciting things coming in the pipeline
so definitely will be much more
opportunity in all of that sense I know
I blurted it all out a little bit out of
order but I had to get all of it out
there so so I didn't forget anything so
there you go no it's perfect it's it's
all great information and I will of
course include in the description a
couple links
um and then you know I'll probably
include whatever like Clips or whatever
I make I will include that info there
and um yeah anybody who's listening uh
you know if if you have my info feel
free to to message me if you have any
questions about my personal experience
um or like if for whatever reason you're
confused about anything like I will um
do my best to kind of be an usher of of
sending you on over over to better you
or just just emphasize I mean I've I've
had great experience with these with all
these people from over there um it's
been really like there's been so much
yes from me like I'm just like down to
the the music is just straight gas I
love it
um like the the initial you know at the
beginning you know there's they
mentioned breath work there's uh
meditations that they send you like all
of it I'm like oh this is so cool I'm so
glad that they included this you know I
didn't think that it was going to be
that in detail when I first got into it
and I would just
um you know so so happy along along the
whole way so um I feel like you guys do
such a good job at better you of
supporting all these aspects and in your
very um aware of the future and like how
you could continue to improve it too you
know we had some discussions yesterday
about kind of some of the things you
guys are looking forward to in the
future and
um yeah it's just so much yes for me I
think there's so so many great resources
and the future of uh not only your
guys's company but just
healing and and you know wellness
centers and and just I think we're
really starting to look at
um the term mental health in such a new
way it's like it's been such like a
weird icky somehow only controlled by
orange pill bottles and like big daddy
Pharma that if we can find a way to to
make it actually help people out you
know in introduces like all aspects of
of Being Human I think that's that's the
way out man it's it's so good so
um yeah
um if there was anything else Megan from
you uh I thank you so much for your time
like this is so cool that you're willing
to come here and chat chat with me for
so long and give me so much your time
like I really hope it sends people over
your guys's way
um was there any any other knots that
you wanted to tie or anything else you
wanted to make sure you mentioned
um I mean the only one I the only
analogy that I did not say was my puzzle
piece analogy which is I think really
helpful in terms I've kind of covered a
little bit
um but it's I say this to people
probably almost every single day and
it's probably like just as effective I
would say as the um like the computer
analogy
um but in terms of like kind of giving
you an idea of how this like treatment
works like kind of what to expect
um it's essentially when you first come
to this imagine that you have a puzzle
piece and this puzzle piece represents
your entire life story all of your
experiences everything that has
essentially LED you up until this point
and made you who you are and basically
you dump out all the puzzle pieces on
the floor now of course you're trying to
look at this you can't make anything
else just one great big you know pile of
chaos nothing is you know you can't see
how anything is connected to one another
or how it's related to anything else you
don't have any context you just hop all
of these individual little random pieces
that you can't really make sense of
again I told talked earlier about the
what the where and the why and when you
don't have all three of those pieces of
information that's what can tend to
overwhelm us and make us like oh my gosh
like I don't know what's going on here I
can't make sense of it because I don't
have all of the pieces that I need so
it's essentially like when you start
with the the sessions it's pretty much
like you you kind of start finding a
couple of puzzle pieces at a time so
it's like okay you know I've done a few
sessions I've I found these pieces right
here and I was able to reassemble these
right here and then this over here here
you know so on and so forth and then to
the point of where you're like okay now
like you know I've reassembled enough to
the point where I can kind of make out
what this is looking like what's
happening over here and then there and
on like basically so on and so forth to
the point of where you've really been
able to essentially reassemble this
whole puzzle piece accidents really only
until this point this is the idea of
once you kind of really get that
neurobiological reset where you get you
know a crazy Epiphany or a breakthrough
and it's kind of just like all of the
little pieces of information that you've
been kind of just having running around
or bouncing around your head and trying
to make sense of now all of it just kind
of can seem to fall into place and
you're able to just look at this full
you know puzzle piece for what it
actually is versus what you thought it
was when you only had the individual
little pieces and you like now you can
see how everything actually connects to
one another and relates to it so now you
can get those three pieces of
information the what the where and the
why right when you're looking at this
part of the puzzle you're like okay I
can see how this it connects to this
piece over here and why when this
happens like it makes me feel like this
or why I then think that I know where
it's coming from why it's happening and
I get that full picture essentially and
that's really once you've been able to
see everything for what it is getting
that kind of outside perspective that's
really where you can look at it
objectively and all of a sudden you know
that that shift in perspective
that is everything that's what ketamine
is incredible for it's the biggest thing
that it allows us to do is when we're so
stuck seeing something from one vantage
point we can't see all the other aspects
that goes into that we're just so
fixated on this one thing it's not until
we then you know move and shift and now
come over here and we're still looking
at the whole same thing but just now
that we're at this angle I can see oh I
couldn't really make this out before
because it just wasn't in my line of
sight now I can get that full picture
and you know take it for what it is and
be able to then now build on this new
Foundation of now that I understand
what's going on where it's coming from
and why it's happening now I can
actually make the changes and start
doing the things that I want you know
that I want to keep that I want to get
rid of and getting to choose what I want
and who I want to be versus having these
things always this essentially choosing
for me and so that's like probably like
my favorite one I would say that I
always like to share because I think it
really helps especially if you have not
started with the treatment yet it gives
you kind of like I said before those
analogies giving you that little bit of
the road map in terms of understanding
setting some expectations of it's not
going to happen overnight it can take
some time it's important to remember
that it does require some patience
um and a little bit of time in the
beginning but just you know keep going
like I said take a day at a time session
at a time and you just keep keep putting
those puzzle pieces together and that
journaling as well that's that's what's
also going to really help you to kind of
find those puzzle pieces and you know
connect those dots essentially so that's
that's basically the only one that I I
wanted to include that's uh definitely
probably my favorite aside from the
computer analogy but uh I hope it helps
and also you can always
um like I said we have a whole team of
people that if you just your interest
did but you're not quite sure if you're
if you're ready to you know take the
leap but you just you want to learn a
little bit more about how it works our
program you know pricing so on so forth
you go to our website
www.betterucare.com uh you can schedule
an intro call with somebody from our
team where like I said briefly before
they'll walk you through our program the
pricing the process and we do have
financing options available so we've
tried to make this as affordable as
possible so that everybody can have
access to it so just want to learn more
you can always have an intro call it's
free of charge you don't have to pay or
commit to anything
um but yeah that's that's basically like
step one or you could always just go to
the website and you know just take the
plunge and you know sign up and then
basically you're still gonna you know
have that communication and the whole
process with us so yeah yeah yeah really
I'm glad that you threw that one in
there your analogies are just you're
slaying with the analogies they're all
so good um yeah you guys I mean if
you're listening and just like like just
do an intro call at least you know
you're not committing to anything yet
maybe you're worried about the the
finance and they'll explain all that to
you just do an intro call it's worth
getting your questions answered if um if
you've made it this far and like you're
really interested in healing something
that's ailing you then you know why not
take the next step maybe this is your
this podcast is your sign to at least do
the intro call you know just check check
them out
um wow this was so great I feel like
this was you know even better than I
could have expected so I'm so again
grateful for your time grateful for
everybody over at better you
um you know give Derek my thanks again
it's all it's all so good
um uh yeah so reach out on social media
I think you guys are a good follow too
anyway I I like following you and seeing
what you post on your stories and in the
new content you come up with too
um I will be
um
yeah I'll include just look down the
description if you're looking for
anything else listeners you know the
deal love yourself drink some water
stretch make sure you're getting some
morning sunlight give yourself a break
you know take take the next step in
healing if that's what's uh whispering
to you so we will see you guys next
episode Megan thank you once again for
your time
see you later everybody this has been
awesome I love to get to see you and
connect
to connect as you know persons you know
to Patient now just you know getting to
talk as to to people along our own
healing Journeys this has been it's been
wonderful thank you so much for having
me yeah it was so cool I'm so glad that
I just like decided to send a little
email I was like yeah let's see if I can
if Megan's available I mean I want to
talk to anybody from over there really
but it was cool that you were available
and um I mean you've been such a perfect
guest for this so I think everybody will
be very grateful with all the
information you've you've provided so
thank you thanks so much have a great
rest of your day everybody
see you guys the junkyard love podcast
[Music]
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age should we learn to have
better conversations with ourselves
[Music]
no
no no no
your knowledge is power
reality is
[Music]
thank you